<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<book>
  <block id="0" location="Farm">
    <text>You are a rancher in the kingdom of Thalos. Your people (and your enemies, the savage Karosseans) have built huge robots for many purposes. With a skilled operator at the controls, a robot can replace a hundred of men - to mine ore, erect buildings, - move cargo, or just about anything else. The robots are also your best defence against the vicious dinosaurs of Thalos. Many years ago, the great lizards caused much destruction. But now mankind has learned to tame the beasts, and many of the folk of Thalos - like you - are dinosaur ranchers. The ranchers use Mark 5A utility robots, known as 'cowboys', to herd the dinosaurs! But wild dinosaurs are still dangerous, and all robots have guns to defend themselves. Early one morning, you are just finishing your breakfast when one of your assistants staggers into the kitchen. 'So sleepy' he says. Then he sits down at the table, pillows his head on his arms and goes to sleep! You shake him, but you cannot rouse him. Alarmed, you go for help. But everyone else you see is asleep. You rush back inside and switch on a radio. But you can get only scraps of messages: 'Everybody asleep... Karossean attack... can't stay awake.. ' Soon there is nothing to be heard. You go outside again and pour cold water on several of your friends - but they just snore and mutter. Then you hear a rumble overhead, like thunder out of the clear sky. You look up. Streaking overhead is the unmistakable shape of a Karossean robojet! You realize what must have happened. Somehow, the Karosseans have managed to put everyone in Thalos to sleep... everyone but you. For some reason, you are immune. Over the next few hours, you listen to the enemy communications and piece together the story. In the past, the Karosseans had steered clear of Thalos; with its brave warriors and its many robots, your land was too tough to attack. But Minos, their leader, hit on a clever plan. His spies spread capsules of a virulent sleeping sickness - and before long, all Thalos was asleep! Soon you hear a broadcast from Minos himself, talking to his invading troops. An elite force of a thousand warriors, with hundreds of robots, has invaded Thalos. But this is only the beginning. With the population helpless, Minos plans to loot your country. Its riches and its robots will be his; its people will be sold as slaves! And only you can stop it... You know what you have to do. You walk back inside and buckle your father's old sword to your waist. Food will be no problem - you know supplies will be easy to find - but you pick up a supply of five medikits. Then you head for the robot parking-area. Alone, you must defeat the Karossean invaders and free your land!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="1">
        <text>Start the adventure!</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="1" location="Farm">
    <text>At the robot parking-area, you stop and look around. There are several robots there, but only two seem suitable for long-distance travel. You study them both. You can take a standard 'cowboy' walking robot, which is not fast, but sturdy and adaptable or a light flyer, which is very speedy and manoeuvrable, but not really intended for combat.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="24">
        <text>Check the cowboy robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="47">
        <text>Check the light flyer.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="2" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>'Insufficient data,' replies the computer. 'Probability of Karossean trick 67 per cent. You have five seconds to change your course.'</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="357">
        <text>Continue to give the computer guardian more data.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="376">
        <text>Turn your robot and go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="3" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Because you are not familiar with this type of robot, you do not get the normal combat bonus with it - in fact, your skill is 1 less than usual while you use it. You realize you had better get out of there while you can.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="147">
        <text>Leave the College of War.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="4" location="Capital City">
    <text>The main encampment of the Karosseans is easy enough to find; they have taken over the city stadium. Even from a distance you can see flying robots wheeling overhead.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="18">
        <text>Approach in your robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="32">
        <text>Go on foot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="5" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>Your path takes you across a shallow swamp; the road is narrow, and the ground to either side looks soft and sticky. When you round a corner, you see a large dinosaur ahead of you. It is not a flesh-eater, but it does not seem disposed to get out of your way.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="239">
        <text>Fight it!</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="95">
        <text>Leave the road.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="6" location="Capital City">
    <text>A blast from the Supertank cracks the pilot's compartment of your robot and vaporizes everything within. You came close to winning and, even in defeat, you shattered the enemy invasion force - but your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="7" location="Capital City">
    <text>You give the proper countersign. The Karossean sentry radios you back: 'Pass, friend!' You have fooled him! You can go about your work.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>Keep exploring the City of Knowledge.</text>
        <condition>context.Page.Location == WorldLocation.CityOfKnowledge</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="132">
        <text>Keep exploring the City of Industry.</text>
        <condition>context.Page.Location == WorldLocation.CityOfIndustry</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="222">
        <text>Keep exploring the Capital City.</text>
        <condition>context.Page.Location == WorldLocation.CapitalCity</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="8" location="City of Storms">
    <text>The sea-coast is a narrow strip of sand, bounded on one side by the ocean and on the other side by steep cliffs. After a few minutes of travel, you see something ahead. It is a huge herd of Brontosaurus dinosaurs. Most of them are munching on seaweed thrown up by the storms, but a few are investigating something that glitters.</text>
    <revisitText>The sea-coast is a narrow strip of sand, bounded on one side by the ocean and on the other side by steep cliffs. After a few minutes of travel, you don't see anything special.</revisitText>
    <choices>
      <choice to="84">
        <text>Investigate it yourself.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>Turn around and go back to the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="9" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>There are several robots here, all identical. They are similar to the Cowboy Robot that you used on your ranch, but more heavily armed and armoured, for use against the largest dinosaurs. These Super-Cowboy Robots move by walking. Each has weapons almost as powerful as those of a war robot. You may take one of these robots if you like.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="129">
        <text>Get in your robot and cross the electro-fence.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Go to the Administrative Building.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Leave the Dinosaur Preserve.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Super Cowboy" frame="Unspecified" armor="14" armorMax="14" speed="Average" speedMax="Average" combatBonus="1" combatBonusMax="1" />
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="10" location="Capital City">
    <text>You decide to visit the Capitol Building, the seat of government of Thalos.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="42">
        <text>Go in your robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="71">
        <text>Travel on foot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="11" location="Capital City">
    <text>The hospital is crawling with Karosseans, both soldiers and doctors. By hiding and skulking, you manage to snatch two medikits. You cannot risk staying longer.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Slip out of the hospital and away.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="12" location="Capital City">
    <text>You are now flying above the city. The storm is incredibly violent. You cannot control your flyer! You have to test your skill.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Test your skill!</text>
        <effect>context.Page.Choices[0].To = context.Die.Roll(2) &gt; context.Player.Skill ? 279 : 316</effect>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="13" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You enter the village and investigate. You find one useful robot, a Digger Robot. This slow but powerful machine rides on treads. It has a bulldozer blade on the front, a scoop-shovel on the back, and two large claws for lifting.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>Explore somewhere else in the City of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Digger" frame="Unspecified" armor="16" armorMax="16" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow" combatBonus="0" combatBonusMax="0">
        <description>Slow, but powerful machine that runs on treads. Has a bulldozer blade on the front, a scoop-shovel on the back and two large claws for lifting.</description>
      </robot>
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="14" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You stay in your robot and travel to the huge Thalian Museum. This is the largest museum in all the land; it is full of exhibits on every imaginable subject. As you approach the museum, you keep a sharp watch, but you see no enemies. When you arrive, you park your robot in front of the building and walk up the steps, past a pair of carved stone dragons. The museum attendant is snoring, but the little Information Robot is alert. 'Can I help you?' it asks. What will you do:</text>
    <revisitText>You stay in your robot and travel to the huge Thalian Museum. This is the largest museum in all the land; it is full of exhibits on every imaginable subject.</revisitText>
    <choices>
      <choice to="160">
        <text>Keep going to the museum.</text>
        <condition>context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="36">
        <text>Ask for military information.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
      <choice to="80">
        <text>Ask for information on sleeping sickness.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
      <choice to="58">
        <text>Ask for information on the Karosseans.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
      <choice to="102">
        <text>Leave the museum.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="15" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The tunnel goes lower and lower into the earth. Then it opens into a wide, dimly lit vault.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="340">
        <text>Enter the vault.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="178">
        <text>Continue downwards.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="16" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You turn north through the deserted city. You see few people lying in the streets here; thinking of the jungle so close by, you shudder. You fear you know what has happened to the people here. Then, rounding the corner, you see that you were right. A Nothosaurus is coming towards you, long tongue flickering. This dinosaur walks on all fours or swims in shallow swamps. It is both a predator and a scavenger. Otherwise, fight the creature. NOTHOSAURUS ARMOUR 7 SPEED Slow SKILL 9</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Nothosaurus" frame="Unspecified" armor="7" armorMax="7" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow">
        <description>A scavenging dinosaur that walks or swims through shallow swamps.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="51" lose="279" escape="331" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="17" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Are looking for something in particular?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Go search something else.</text>
        <condition>!context.Inventory.Contains("Cloak Model Reference")</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="53">
        <text>Search for the Cloak of Invisibility.</text>
        <condition>context.Inventory.Contains("Cloak Model Reference")</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="18" location="Capital City">
    <text>How will you approach the enemy encampment?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="55">
        <text>Fly towards it.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="187">
        <text>Travel on the ground.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="19" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You hear a crashing sound in the jungle, coming towards you. It is a low, armoured dinosaur, waving a club-like tail back and forth. It is coming straight at you.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="400">
        <text>Attack the Dinosaur.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="115">
        <text>Flee!</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="20" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The whole sixth floor of the Centre seems to be a cross between a laboratory and a gymnasium. In the middle of the room is a device like a suit of armour. Beside it is a sleeping fellow, somewhat battered around the face, in an athletic suit. After a little investigation, you find that the device on the floor is an experimental 'Amplifier Suit', designed to make its wearer almost as strong and last as a robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="83">
        <text>Try the Amplifier Suit.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>Try another floor instead.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="21" location="City of Worship">
    <text>You flee in fear out of the temple. You can feel the disapproval of the Powers of Glory. Lose 1 luck point and 1 skill point for your cowardice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Visit another part of the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <effects>
      <effect>context.Player.Skill -= 1</effect>
      <effect>context.Player.Luck -= 1</effect>
    </effects>
  </block>
  <block id="22" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>You use the code-words you found with the map reference. 'Acceptable,' crackles the voice of the guardian computer. 'Entering at Clearance Level Zero.'</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="175">
        <text>Enter the building.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="23" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>Unfortunately, this experimental craft is different from all other robots you have handled. Its Combat Bonus of 2 does not count for you until you have been through two combats with it.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="378">
        <text>Leave the City of Pleasure.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="24" location="Farm">
    <text>This man-shaped robot is designed for dinosaur herding. It moves by walking. It has weapons for dealing with rogue dinosaurs, but they are not as powerful as those of a war robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="47">
        <text>Check the light flyer.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="70" showWhenDisabled="true">
        <text>Chose a place to go.</text>
        <condition>context.Robot is not null</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Cowboy" frame="Humanoid" armor="10" armorMax="10" speed="Average" speedMax="Average" combatBonus="0" combatBonusMax="0">
        <description>A man-shaped robot designed for dinosaur herding</description>
      </robot>
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="25" location="City of Industry">
    <text>This is the Robot Experimental Centre. You know little about the Centre except its name, but you have heard rumours that top-secret work is being done here.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="251">
        <text>Keep exploring the centre.</text>
        <condition>context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>Keep exploring the centre.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="26" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are being attacked by a Karossean Air-Fighter! ntis is a sleek, arrow-shaped robot. It can sprout legs to land on the ground, but it always fights in the shape of an aircraft.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Air Fighter" frame="Unspecified" armor="7" armorMax="7" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A sleek, arrow shaped flying Karossean robot.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="113" lose="136" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="27" location="Capital City">
    <text>This Karossean robot is like nothing you have encountered before. It is a Crusher, a humanoid robot, but twice as large as those you have seen before. It has no guns, but was designed for destroying forts and trenches. It attacks by stamping with its huge feet. You cannot Escape. CRUSHER ARMOUR 14 SPEED Slow SKILL 8 SPECIAL ABILITIES: Although the Crusher is not especially skilful, every time it hits it does double damage. Thus, it does 4 with a normal strike, or 2 if you use LUCK successfully, or 6 if you try LUCK and fail!</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Crusher" frame="Unspecified" armor="14" armorMax="14" skill="8" skillMax="8" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow">
        <description>A gigantic fort-destroying humanoid robot that does double damage when it hits.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="275" lose="384" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="28" location="Capital City">
    <text>You quickly activate the controls to turn your robot into its flying form. The transition, usually so swift, seems incredibly slow in the face of the rampaging herd... but in the nick of time you swoop away.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="62">
        <text>Wait until the dinosaurs have dispersed, then land to see what they were looking at.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>Go back to the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="29" location="Capital City">
    <text>You put on the Cloak of Invisibility and explore the hospital. Although the building is full of enemies, the Cloak lets you pass among them without being spotted. You find a robot surgeon which heals your wounds: restore your STAMINA to its Initial level. You also find two medikits in an unguarded room. You find nothing else of any particular use. At length, your Cloak begins to flicker; you will not be able to use it again. You return to your robot..</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Return to your robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="30" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have defeated the Tripods, but you hear more enemies on the way. You have time for only one choice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="68">
        <text>Examine the wreckage of the Tripods.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="132">
        <text>Enter the fuel plant.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="31" location="Capital City">
    <text>You decide to explore the streets of the Capital City. How will you travel: Flying about? Ground travel, going left? Ground travel, going right?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="55">
        <text>Flying about?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="153">
        <text>Ground travel, going left?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="290">
        <text>Ground travel, going right?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="32" location="Capital City">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="90">
        <text>If you possess the Cloak of Invisibility and have not used it.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="103">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="33" location="Capital City">
    <text>Giving the odd-looking plant a wide berth, you continue on your path.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="237">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="34" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You decide to wander around and see what you can find. The streets are choked with huge vehicles, stranded where they fell or rolled when their pilots went to sleep.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="342">
        <text>If you explore to the east.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="195">
        <text>If you go west.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="35" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You have defeated the Karossean ambush. All three robots lie smashed and burning on the ground. What will you do: Explore the city? Explore the jungle? Leave the city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="366">
        <text>Explore the city?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="170">
        <text>Explore the jungle?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="298">
        <text>Leave the city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="36" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>'Well, that depends on what kind of information you need. modern military information is classified, and you would have to ask at the War College. Historical military information is in Hall Beta. We have some wonderful exhibits.' If you ask for something else, ask something else.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="146">
        <text>' If you go to Hall Beta to look at the military exhibits.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>If you ask for something else.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="37" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your prayer is quickly answered. A blanket Of peace comes over you the same peace that the other worshippers received. You feel yourself falling asleep. Perhaps the Powers of Peace will protect you from the Karosseans somehow, but your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="38" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Choose how you are travelling.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>If you are travelling on the ground.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="313">
        <text>If you are flying.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="39" location="City of Industry">
    <text>After several hours Of travel, you enter rocky terrain. The path narrows, and you are forced to use both of your robot's hands just to climb. You wish you were in a vehicle that could just fly over all this! Suddenly, you hear a roar. Looking behind you, you see a huge Tyrannosaurus sprinting through the rocks at you! Jaws agape, it lunges towards you, and robot and dinosaur fall to the ground, grappling fiercely. This huge meat-eater is the 'king of the dinosaurs', and attacks anything it sees to feed its savage appetite. You must fight it to the finish.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Tyrannosaurus" frame="Dinosaur" armor="8" armorMax="8" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>This huge meat-eater is the king of the dinosaurus.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="235" lose="258" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="40" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You have returned to the City of Knowledge. In the distance, you see the towers of the College of Medicine. But you also see a Karossean air-fighter, clos ing fast! If you know a password With which to challenge the enemy, that number. If you do not know the password.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="305">
        <text>If you do not know the password.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="41" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>At the airfield, you find dozens of pleasure craft Of all sorts, none of which looks useful. But parked in an out-of-the-way corner is a small but deadlylooking fighting-machine. It is a sleek experimental i fighter, called a Wasp Fighter. Only a few exist. It has very little armour, but it has good weapons and handles well. WASP FIGHTER ARMOVR6 SPEED Very Fast COMBAT BONUS2 SPECIAL ABILITIES: Whenever the Wasp's Attack Roll exceeds its foe's roll by 4 or more, it has literally flown circles around its foe! It auto. matically Wins the next combat round as well — no rolls are necessary. You may take it if you like. If you return here later, your old robot will be here instead of the Wasp.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="165">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="42" location="Capital City">
    <text>The closer you get to the building, the more Karosseans you see. Soon you realize that your robotjs making you far too conspicuous.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="71">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="43" location="City of Storms">
    <text>You are leaving the City of Storms. Where would you like to go: The City of Knowledge? The City of Worship? The City of the Guardians? Note that you cannot visit the City of the Guardians until you know the numbers to use in place Of 'XX'.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>The City of Knowledge?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>The City of Worship?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="44" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The lift doors clang shut and it begins to descend. After about five minutes, it Stops again. Outside is a corridor even dimmer than the area you just left. The door opens just wide enough for you to squeeze out. Will you press another button, or step out and go down the corridor?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="269">
        <text>Will you press another button (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="15">
        <text>), or step out and go down the corridor (.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="45" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You return to the robot that brought you to the city. You collect your Possessions and climb out of the one you used in the jungle. Just as you reach the ground, you hear a thunderous explosion. You have been ambushed! Your old robot is going up in flames. Behind you, guns are firing at the one that took you through the jungle.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="347">
        <text>If you climb back into that robot and fight.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="159">
        <text>If you run for cover.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="46" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You charge to the attack! The Karossean controlling the other robot is caught totally by surprise. Roll two dice and do that much damage to the enemy robot before its pilot can react. Otherwise, mark off the damage you did, and fight.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="109">
        <text>If you roll 12.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="78">
        <text>Otherv.'ise.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="47" location="Farm">
    <text>This flyingrobot, called a Dragonfly Model D, looks like a gigantic dragonfly, complete with buzzing wings. Its main advantage in combat is its speed.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="70">
        <text>Choose a place to go.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="24">
        <text>Check the Cowboy Robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Dragonfly" frame="Unspecified" armor="5" armorMax="5" speed="Static" speedMax="Static" combatBonus="0" combatBonusMax="0" />
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="48" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You step over the fragments of the smashed robot and enter the laboratory. Inside, you find something very interesting: the prototype for a Seeker Missile. There is only one, but it looks very handy. It can be attached to the outside of any robot. It can be used only when you are piloting a robot - not in personal combat. It may be fired at any time, between Attack Rounds. It will automatically hit its target and reduce its ARMOUR score by 10. As you take your prize downstairs, you see another Guard Robot like the one you defeated. You hurry out of the lobby and back to your robot. You may install the Seeker Missile now, or save it for another robot. It may be moved from one robot to another, but it is lost if the robot carrying it is lost, or if it is fired.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="206">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="49" location="City of Worship">
    <text>Which temple would you like to visit: The Temple of Peace? The Temple of Fear? The Temple of Nothingness? The Temple of Glory?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="365">
        <text>The Temple of Peace?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="304">
        <text>The Temple of Fear?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="249">
        <text>The Temple of Nothingness?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="339">
        <text>The Temple of Glory?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="50" location="Capital City">
    <text>The Karossean troops, already nervous because of the reports of Thalian robots at large, don't hesitate. They set off a buried mine, placed beneath the gate as a precaution. Your robot is shattered. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="51" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You have destroyed the scavenging Nothosaurus. Add 2 LUCK points for protecting the sleeping people from this menace. If you have not already explored the south of the city, you may do so.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="225">
        <text>Explore the south of the city.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>Go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="52" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>_e 52 You've fought robots, and you've fought dinosaurs, but this hybrid foe is too much for you. The beating your robot took has injured you: Jose 2 STAMINA points. As your battered robot pulls away, you hear the mechanical Tyrannosaurus give a mechanical scream behind you. You had best go elsewhere; you don't want to be here when the Karosseans come to find out What has happened! You leave; you may not Return to the museum again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="53" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>In a closet, you find What appears to be an unused coat-hanger — but when you pick it up, it is heavy! You have found the Cloak of Invisibility. Inside it are the instructions. When it is activated, it will cause light waves to pass around you, making you invisible for about an hour. But it will only work once without being recharged, and the instructions do not say how to recharge it.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="54" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are at the Collegeof Medicine. This is both the greatest hospital and the greatest medical labora­tory of your entire nation. You approach cautiously, but see no sign of the Karossean invaders. You leave your robot near the front steps.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="232">
        <text>Enter the building.</text>
        <condition>context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="77">
        <text>Seek treatment for your own injuries.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
      <choice to="126">
        <text>Look for information on the sleeping sickness.</text>
        <condition>!context.Page.IsVisited</condition>
        <effect>context.Page.IsVisited = true</effect>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="55" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your robot takes to the air, and you can soon see the enemy encampment. But the enemy air patrols are vigilant: two flying robots swoop to challenge you. They do not ask for a password, but open fire immediately. You must fight these two Myrmidon robots. The Myrmidon is the standard Karossean combat robot. It has two forms - humanoid and fighter-plane. These two are in plane form and will not try to change during the battle. SPECIAL ABILITIES: None.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="First Myrmidon" frame="Unspecified" armor="8" armorMax="8" skill="11" skillMax="11" speed="Very Fast" speedMax="Very Fast">
        <description>A Karossean Myrmidon in fighter-plane form.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" lose="125" />
      </monster>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Second Myrmidon" frame="Unspecified" armor="8" armorMax="8" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Very Fast" speedMax="Very Fast">
        <description>A Karossean Myrmidon in fighter-plane form.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="75" lose="125" escape="98" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="56" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have defeated the Ankylosaurus. Looking along the trail of destroyed vegetation that it left behind, you see a glint of metal.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="263">
        <text>If you investigate.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="321">
        <text>If you ignore it and go on.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="57" location="Capital City">
    <text>Soon your robot is parked in front Of the Temple Of Fear. It is a huge, irregularly shaped building, built entirely from black Stone. Within it are served the Powers of Fear. If you are having second thoughts about your visit, you may return.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>If you are having second thoughts about your visit, you may.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="193">
        <text>If you Wish to go inside.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="58" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You make your way to Hall Epsilon. The trip is a long one, and several times you hear odd echoing sounds. You realize that you are not alone in the building! You press on, and find the exhibition on the history of the Karossoans. Studying it briefly, you see that it has nothing to do with their military abilities; it is all about their culture and customs. It will take an hour to study the material.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="180">
        <text>Study the material.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="224">
        <text>Return to the front desk.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="59" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Before long, you have put the equipment to work on your own robot. Restore your robot's ARMOUR score to its Initial value. As you finish yourwork, the machines' programming powers them down. You try, but you cannot restart them. You may not return here for further repairs. You find nothing else Of interest in the shop.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="110">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="60" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You can tell that your robot is nearly done for. If you would rather fight to a finish, return and complete the battle.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="183">
        <text>If you would like to bail out of your crippled machine.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="341">
        <text>If you would rather fight to a finish.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="61" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Your luck can't last for ever, since you are withouta robot in a hostile city. Eventually you are spotted and captured. When your countrymen awake, they join you in the slave-pens. Some day you may escape, but for now your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="62" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The dinosaurs were investigating a Cowboy robot — possibly belonging to their herder — which is half buried in the sand. The machine proves to be unsalvageable, but within its cockpit you find two medikits. You may add these to your Possessions and continue. You cannot return to the seashore.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="63" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Where would you like to go: The Thalian Museum? The College of Medicine? The College of War? The Dinosaur Preserve? Out of the city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="160">
        <text>The Thalian Museum?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="54">
        <text>The College of Medicine?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="277">
        <text>The College of War?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="66">
        <text>The Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="380">
        <text>Out of the city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="64" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You set Off into the jungle — a brave move, but a foolish one! A prowling dinosaur snaps you up so quickly that you hardly have time to realize your danger. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="65" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You park your robot beside the door and enter the College ot War. You are alert for other Karosseans, but apparently the sentry outside was the only one. The halls and rooms are littered with beribboned generals, fast asleep. Following the signs, you head for the library to see what you can learn. But, just as you get there, you hear a roaring sound from outside. Looking out of the window, you see three sleek fighter-planes hurtle down, sprout legs and turn into robots like the sentry outside. The Karosseans are arriving in force! You quickly look around the room. There are sev eral volumes on the counter, as though someone was trying to check them out just before the sleep ing sickness hit. The books are too large to carry, and you have time to look at only one. Which title will you choose: The City Of the Gnardians? Emergency Procedures? Yarossean Military Rot.vts?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="256">
        <text>The City Of the Gnardians?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="300">
        <text>Emergency Procedures?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="268">
        <text>Yarossean Military Rot.vts?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="66" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are at the entrance to the Dinosaur Preserve, where some of the wildest and most vicious creatures of all Thalos are kept for study. If you have already been here, return immediately. Otherwise, keep reading. An electro-fence keeps the creatures from rampaging out. On your side of the fence is cool green grass; on the other side is rank jungle. Also on your side of the fence are two buildings: the Administrative Building, and a huge, unmarked, barn-like structure. What will you do?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="189">
        <text>If you have already been here.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Leave your robot and go to the Administrative Building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="171">
        <text>Leave your robot and go to the other building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="129">
        <text>Stay in your robot and cross the electro-fence?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="67" location="City of Worship">
    <text>Storm clouds are gathering as you approach. But even through the static on your radio, you can hear chatter in Karossean voices. Then you are challenged by several Karosseans in small robots.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="217">
        <text>If you fight them.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="12">
        <text>If you fly away from them.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="68" location="City of Worship">
    <text>You check the wrecked Tripods. You are in luck! Thanks to their modular design, one has a piece of undamaged armour-plate that will fit any robot. You can attach it now, or save it until later (though you may not install it during a battle). It will restore t point of ARMOUR, though this may not raise your roboes ARMOUR score above its Initial score. It may be used only once!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="293">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="69" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You leave the building on foot. The smashed remains of your robot lie in the street outside; the ones you fought are nowhere to be seen. You will have to explore the city on foot in hope of finding something. You cannot go to another city until you find a robot; if you have to fight a dinosaur, you will be in trouble! Where Will you go: The north part Of the city? The south part of the city? The jungle?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="16">
        <text>The north part Of the city?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="225">
        <text>The south part of the city?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="64">
        <text>The jungle?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="70" location="Farm">
    <text>Now what are you going to do? You know that, although there are probably Karosseans every­ where, their base is at the Capital City. But you can't just charge in there and attack them with your little robot! You must prepare well before you make your move. Fortunately, there are many cities in Thalos. You will be able to search the whole country for help, if need be, before you confront the invaders. Two large cities are fairly close.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="93">
        <text>Got to the city of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="209">
        <text>Go to the city of Industry.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="71" location="Capital City">
    <text>You decide to go on foot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="106">
        <text>If you possess the Cloak of Invisibility and have not used it, you may use it now.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="134">
        <text>If you have already used it, do not possess it, or if you simply choose not to use it.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="72" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The tunnel continues on and levels out again. Lose t STAMINA point. Eventually it opens up into a large area filled with dimly visible hulks.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="340">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="73" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Almost immediately the path forks again. To the left, a large sign reads 'Danger! Man-trap!' There is no sign by the right path.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="128">
        <text>If you go left.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="188">
        <text>If you go right.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="74" location="Capital City">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="219">
        <text>If you seek treatment for your own injuries.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="395">
        <text>If you look for information on sleeping sickness.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="75" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have eliminated the two enemy robots— but at a cost. You are somewhat shaken up by the manoeuvres you have been forced to perform; lose STAMINA point. More foes are approaching rapidly.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="245">
        <text>If you press on towards the encampment.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="98">
        <text>If you retreat.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="76" location="Capital City">
    <text>You continue through the enemy encampment. Soon you can see the wide barrier separating the main encampment from the Karossean officers' territory. There are not many robots near by, but the ones you can see are formidable. One of them signals you. 'Halt! What's the password?' What will you do: Reply 'Eighty-eight'? Attack immediately? Reply 'Minos'?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="120">
        <text>Reply 'Eighty-eight'?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="264">
        <text>Attack immediately?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="145">
        <text>Reply 'Minos'?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="77" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You turn your steps towards the hospital section Of the College of Medicine. Soon you find a medikit, which you may add to your Possessions. What will you do now: Continue to search the hospital? Look for information on sleeping sickness? Leave the hospital?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="185">
        <text>Continue to search the hospital?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="126">
        <text>Look for information on sleeping sickness?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="210">
        <text>Leave the hospital?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="78" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You fight the enemy robot. It is a Myrmidon, the standard Karossean combat robot. It has two forms - humanoid and fighter-plane. This one is in humanoid form and will not be able to change itself during the battle. MYRMIDON ARMOUR 12 SPEED Medium SKILL 10 SPECIAL ABILITIES: None for this battle.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Myrmidon" frame="Unspecified" armor="12" armorMax="12" skill="10" skillMax="10" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A Karossean Myrmidon in humanoid form.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="109" lose="133" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="79" location="Unknown">
    <text>You play for another twenty minutes. When the time ends, the machine goes dark; you will not be able to play it again. But the detailed simulation of combat in the Wasp 200 Fighter has added to your SKILL (with robots only).</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="288">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="80" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Tm sorry,' replies the Information Robot. 'We have a general medical display in Hall Omicron, but for the kind of specific information you want, you would need to inquire at a hospital, or at the College of Medicine.' If you want to leave the museum, turn tot02. If you want to ask another question, return and make another choice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>If you want to ask another question.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="81" location="Unknown">
    <text>You decide to investigate the Capital City hospital.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="99">
        <text>If you want to Stay in your robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="152">
        <text>If you investigate on foot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="82" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The junkyard is just as you left it, but the huge Ape is nowhere in sight. There is nothing that you can do here.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="110">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="83" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You fit yourself into the Amplifier Device and acti vate it. When you take an experimental step, you jump a metre in the air! You reach for the instructions on a nearby table— and your fist goes through the table! You are delighted. You pick up a hundredkilo file cabinet With one hand, toss it in the air and catch it. Then you try to jump. Maybe you can go over tall buildings with a single bound! At that point, the suit goes out of control. You bounce off several walls, the floor, and once the ceiling. Eventually you come toa stop. You carefully deactivate the suit— then you just lie and rest. Lose 2 STAMINA points. Now you know why you never heard Of this experiment, and Why the tester in the sweatsuit looked so battered! If you want to investigate elsewhere, return and make a new choice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="206">
        <text>If you leave the building.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>If you want to investigate elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="84" location="City of Storms">
    <text>The inquisitive dinosaurs totally surround your quarry. What will you do: Shove your way in among them? Fire a few shots to panic them? Shout at them over your speakers?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="387">
        <text>Shove your way in among them?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="299">
        <text>Fire a few shots to panic them?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="119">
        <text>Shout at them over your speakers?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="85" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are inside the Administrative Building. Everyone is asleep, Of course. You see nothing Of special interest. What will you do now: Look for a specific object? Search the whole Office thoroughly? Investigate the other building? Get in your robot and cross the electro-fence? Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="17">
        <text>Look for a specific object?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="96">
        <text>Search the whole Office thoroughly?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="171">
        <text>Investigate the other building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="129">
        <text>Get in your robot and cross the electro-fence?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="86" location="Capital City">
    <text>You summon your courage and confront the Powers Of Nothingness. You may not know the meaning of life, but you know you have a mission. And suddenly, nothing feels strange. You stalk out of the Temple of Nothingness. You have gained nothing... and lost nothing. Restore the LUCK point that you lost when Testing your Luck, and return.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Restore the LUCK point that you lost when Testing your Luck, and.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="87" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="177">
        <text>If you are wearing an enemy uniform.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="199">
        <text>If you do not have a uniform, Test your Luck: if you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="223">
        <text>if you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="88" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>'Eighty-eight!' you bark at the Karosseans. 'Seven!' they reply to you. Aha! You have learned the countersign to their password! And because you gave the password, you are free to go about your business. Where were you when you challenged the enemy soldiers: The City of Industry? The City Of Knowledge? The Capital City?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="132">
        <text>The City of Industry?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>The City Of Knowledge?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="192">
        <text>The Capital City?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="89" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>Your captors discuss what to do with you. Eventual iy they toss you into a basement room and lock the door. All your Possessions are lost.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="315">
        <text>If you try to escape now.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="397">
        <text>If you bide your time and wait for a better chance.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="90" location="Capital City">
    <text>Using the Cloak of Invisibility, you easily slip through the enemy lines and into their officers' camp. There you spy Minos himself!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="201">
        <text>If you attack him by surprise.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="103">
        <text>If you shed your Cloak and try another stratagem.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="91" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Fortunately, the problem seems to be nothing worse than a pair of crossed wires. You activate the robot surgeon and tell it you need treatment. Lights blinking and motors humming, it obliges. Restore all lost STAMINA points and 1 LUCK point.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="126">
        <text>If you nowlook for information on sleeping sickness.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="210">
        <text>If you leave the building.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="92" location="Capital City">
    <text>There are no Karosseans left in sight, but you know you had better be off before more appear! return.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Return to the Capital City.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="93" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You head for the City Of Knowledge. It is your people's greatest centre of learning. There, you hope, you will find information that Will help you defeat the invaders. After about an hour of travel, you sight a flying dinosaur ahead of you. It dives aggressively towards you. You must fight it. It is a Pteranodon, a large, predatory flying dinosaur. It is lightly built, but speedy and aggressive.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Pteranodon" frame="Dinosaur" armor="3" armorMax="3" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A large predatory flying dinosaur.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="186" lose="116" escape="186" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="94" location="Unknown">
    <text>The stairway leads to a corridor which turns downward once again. Eventually, the corridor ends in a small alcove with a lift. Rather than retrace your steps, you enter the lift and push the button.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="44">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="95" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>This is a fatal mistake: you quickly sink into the swampy goo. The dinosaur watches, bemused, as bubbles rise to mark your resting-place.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="96" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>In trying to open an Office marked 'Private', you activate a security system. An electric shock pins you to the door-frame. By the time you get free, you have lost STAMINA point.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="97" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>battle is over. You have torn the Man-trap Plant into a thousand pieces. Nothing remains of the vicious vegetable except a damper spot on the marshy ground.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="237">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="98" location="Capital City">
    <text>You realize that you cannot win a dogfight against this many foes. Dodging and weaving between the buildings of the Capital City, you lose your pur suers. You have stirred up a hornets' nest now! You must press the attack before they hunt you down. What will you do: Look elsewhere in the Capital City for help? 30S Try to slip into the enemy camp on foot? Stay in your robot and attack on the ground?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="30">
        <text>Look elsewhere in the Capital City for help?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="32">
        <text>S Try to slip into the enemy camp on foot?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="187">
        <text>Stay in your robot and attack.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="99" location="Unknown">
    <text>As you round a corner, you see a pair Of Karossean robots coming your way! Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="130">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="172">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="100" location="Unknown">
    <text>too When your instruments tell you that you penetrated to the heart of the storm, you take precious flask of Blue Potion and unstopper it. Yot quickly pour it through the ejection lock. It diffuses in the air around you. You smile; you know storm will quickly carry it to every part of Thalos But when ycu land, the people of the City o: Worship are still asleep. Obviously, the Potion was not sufficiently potent.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="101" location="Unknown">
    <text>You have defeated the Tylosaurus. Small scavengers are already appearing in the water around you, drawn by the blood.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="62">
        <text>If you continue towards the spot where you saw the herd of dinosaurs.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="102" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You find a stairway and head down. You find that both the Karosseans are dead. One was about your size; you quickly strip off his unifonn and put it on yourself. It may come in handy later! You check the signs. The demolished exhibit was labelled 'Tyrannosaurus'. The shouts from outside are coming closer, so you duck out of a convenient door.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="1014">
        <text>Return to the front desk.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="103" location="Capital City">
    <text>The enemy encampment is well patrolled. You are seized by Karossean guards. If you know something that might help you now, the reference number that came with that information.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="228">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="104" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Looking at a hospital map, you see that the Research Lab is not far away. Carrying the book with you, you set off to find it, and soon arrive at a large chemical laboratory. As you walked, you heard strange squeaks and shuffling noises in the hallway, but saw nothing. You are somewhat disturbed to note that there are no sleeping doctors or researchers here! No one is here at all. You bar the lab doors for safety and set to work. fortunately, the instructions are clear and the lab is still stocked. Eventually, you havea one-litre flask of Blue Potion - all you can make with the materials in hand. Indeed, from the rarity of the materials you used, you doubt that another litre could be made in the whole of Thalos! But you also know from the that one litre would be enough for everyone in Thalos. Nevertheless, there is a problem. The potion is so volatile that once opened, if will quickly evaporate; you cannot awaken people one at a time. You must find a way to treat your whole nation at once! So your quest is not over. Outside, you hear the strange squeaking once again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="394">
        <text>Leave immediately.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="372">
        <text>Remain the laboratory and check the work one last time.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="105" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You realize that you cannot win a dogfight against this many foes. Dodging and weaving between the buildings of the Capital City, you lose your pursuers. You have stirred up a hornets' nest now! You must press the attack before they hunt you down. What will you do?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="394">
        <text>If you leave immediately.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="372">
        <text>If you emain in the laboratory, checking your work one ust time.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="23">
        <text>You decide to visit the Fuel-refining Plant. This i where the radioactive ores that power the robots an processed. A single block of fuel will drive a robo for a year. As you approach, you realize that someo the robots standing around the plant are active! Karosseans have sent a force to garrison thi strategic point. What will you do: Proceed normally?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="16">
        <text>Attack?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="13">
        <text>Flee?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="19">
        <text>Try a ruse?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="106" location="Capital City">
    <text>You don the Cloak. It works like a charm: when yo walk in front Of a store window, you have reflection! Soon the Cloak is put to a harder test: yo walk in front of a Karossean patrol, but remai totally unseen. You enter the Capitol Building itsel There is no sign Of the legislators; you assume the have been taken away as hostages. While you at investigating the building. you observe a pair Karosseans standing guard over a huge displé case. You move closer and listen. 'That's right,' one is saying. 'Minos will come to take possession of this sword in a few hours. There'll be some kind of ceremony, I guess.' Looking in the case, you see that this is the Sword of State! You are reluctant to leave it where the tyrant can get it — but taking it would be a risk. What will you do: Go on and look elsewhere in the Capitol Building? Try to take the sword by stealth? t Attack the sentries and take the sword?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="164">
        <text>Go on and look elsewhere in the Capitol Building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="190">
        <text>Try to take the sword by stealth?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="215">
        <text>t Attack the sentries and take the sword?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="107" location="Capital City">
    <text>You pray to the Powers of Peace to grant you and your people the peace that can only come from freedom. Somewhere you seem to hear bells chiming. and a feeling of well-being comes over you. Restore your LUCK to its Initial score. 7 you may not visit this temple again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="108" location="Capital City">
    <text>Having provoked a battle, you must now finish it The enemy robot turns and attacks. It is a Battleman, a heavy-duty Karossean combat robot.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Battleman" frame="Humanoid" armor="11" armorMax="11" skill="11" skillMax="11" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A heavy duty Karossean combat robot.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="290" lose="61" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="109" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The enemy robot falls, blasted to scrap. There is no sign of its pilot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="155">
        <text>If you want to examine the fallen robot more carefully.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="65">
        <text>If you want to ignore it and enter the War College.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="110" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You continue to wander about the city for some time. You see many interesting sights, but nothing that looks as though it would help. At length you come to a large open area. At one side of the park is a large building marked 'Robot Experimental Centre'. Across the park is a sign that says 'Robots Working'. It looks like an open access to the citys tunnel system. Will you visit the Robot Experimental Centre, or leave your robot and enter the tunnel system?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="25">
        <text>Will you visit the Robot Experimental Centre (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="127">
        <text>), or leave your robot and enter the tunnel system (.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="111" location="Capital City">
    <text>What will you do: Challenge Minos to a personal duel? Claim to be a message-bearer? Use a password? Try to fight your way out?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="253">
        <text>Challenge Minos to a personal duel?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="267">
        <text>Claim to be a message-bearer?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="173">
        <text>Use a password?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="283">
        <text>Try to fight your way out?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="112" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>In the 'Dinosaur Hunt' game, you are given a huge gun with which to fire at holograms representing dinosaurs of all kinds. You fire for a while, but the game is very unrealistic and boring. The dinosaurs seem to walk right past, unaware that they are targets. You leave in disgust. But, as you do, you notice a plaque by the door. It reads, in part, this game is based on the prototype "Cloak of Invisibility" device, Model 3, now being tested at the Dinosaur Preserve.' Very interesting!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="288">
        <text>If you want to play another game.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="165">
        <text>If you would rather leave the arcade.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="113" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The enemy robot, trailing smoke, ploughs into the ground. Nothing could have survived that blast. You are free to go.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="114" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>1 You spy an open closet in an adjoining room. Inside you can see a medikit! You investigate; sure enough, the rest of your equipment is here! But as you are gathering it, a rifle-butt strikes your head from behind. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="115" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You hurriedly move to the side. The creature blunders past you and vanishes. You are on the outskirts of the City of the Jungle.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="73">
        <text>If you re-enter the jungle, on the other path.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>If you want to go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="116" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="139">
        <text>If you have a flying robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="162">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="117" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You cross the electro-fence into the Dinosaur Preserve itself. Small lizards scurry about as your robot passes. For several minutes you explore, finding nothing of interest. Then you hear a coughing, trumpeting sound. Charging towards you are two huge, horned Triceratops. Underneath the jungle canopy, shape-changing robots cannot change to flying form; you will have to fight these foes on the ground. You must fight them both at once. Each dinosaur will have a separate attack on you in each Attack Round, but you must choose which of the two you will fight. Attack your chosen foe each round as in a normal battle. Against the other you must throw for your Attack Strength in the normal way, but even if your Attack Strength is greater, you will not wound it. You must just count this as though you have defended yourself from it. However, if its Attack Strength is greater, it will damage your robot in the usual way.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="First Triceratops" frame="Dinosaur" armor="9" armorMax="9" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A huge horned dinosaur.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" lose="310" />
      </monster>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Second Triceratops" frame="Dinosaur" armor="10" armorMax="10" skill="8" skillMax="8" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A huge horned dinosaur.</description>
        <battleOutcome lose="310" win="291" escape="270" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="118" location="Unknown">
    <text>You nee down the stairs. If you ever Return to this floor, the Guard Robot will still be there, with whatever damage it took during this battle. You find yourself back in the lobby.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="119" location="City of Storms">
    <text>They ignore you totally.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="84">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="120" location="Capital City">
    <text>'Wrong password, soldier!' comes the response. 'You're in officer territory. Wait! Stop! That's the Thalian! But as the huge sentry robot attacks, you fire also.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="27">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="121" location="Unknown">
    <text>You run, but the Nothosaurus is faster. It gobbles you up in two gulps. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="122" location="Unknown">
    <text>Your radio suddenly crackles to life with a mechanical voice. you are approaching the City of the Guardians. Please give your authorization.' If you have read a military volume on the City of the Guardians, the map reference you were given there. If you have not read this volume.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="218">
        <text>If you have not read this volume.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="123" location="Capital City">
    <text>You enter the temple, but soon find that nothing is what it appears to be. Indeed, nothing is happening here. You seem to have gained nothing by having come. But then, nothing would be served by your leaving! Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="86">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="204">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="124" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>'Oh, very good', the little robot responds. 'We have a wonderful exhibition on Karossean history and culture in Hall Epsilon'.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="124">
        <text>Go to Hall Epsilon to study Karossean history.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>Ask something more up to date.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="125" location="Capital City">
    <text>As your faithful robot disintegrates around you, you hit the 'Eject' button. Test your Luck. If you are Unlucky, the ejection system was destroyed in the fight, and your adven ture ends here.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="176">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="126" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You follow the signs to the Medical Library. There, amid huge, dusty stacks of books, you begin your search. Finally, in an old textbook, you find a clue to help you. It describes a medicine that - so it says - will instantly cure all types of sleeping sickness.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="104">
        <text>Compound the medicine.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="210">
        <text>Leave the hospital.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="127" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You park your robot outside the tunnel entrance and slip inside. You don't know what you expect to find here, but you have never been in this tunnel system, and its aura of secrecy attracts you. The tunnels are dimly lit, but you can see well enough. Soon you come to a turning.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="15">
        <text>If you go right.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="240">
        <text>If you go left.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="128" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Soon you arrive at a large clearing. In the middle of the clearing is a huge plant with many spiky leaves. In the centre Of the plant, barely within reach, is a stalk bearing several huge red-and-yellow blos soms. What will you do: Examine the plant more carefully? Pick a flower? Circle around the plant and continue?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="292">
        <text>Examine the plant more carefully?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="373">
        <text>Pick a flower?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="33">
        <text>Circle around the plant and continue?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="129" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Note that with some robots, you have a choice between flying or walking!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="252">
        <text>If you fly over the jungle of the Preserve.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="117">
        <text>If you enter the jungle on the ground.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="130" location="Unknown">
    <text>You draw back and freeze your robot into immobile ity, hugging the corner of a building. Amazingly, they walk right by! You hear a scrap of talk on the radio: around here somewhere. When they have passed, you proceed to the hospital.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="192">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="131" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="359">
        <text>If you are in the Wasp Fighter.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="378">
        <text>If you are in any other robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="132" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>Still in your robot, you enter the fuel plant and look around. The building is full of gleaming machinery and stacked canisters of fuel, each worth its weight in gold. But you see nothing that appears likely to help you in your struggle. Furthermore, since your robot was not designed to enter this dangerous environment, you lose STAM INA point because of the radioactivity.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="293">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="133" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Test your Luck. If you are Lucky, you manage to guide your crippled robot around the corner before it collapses. If you are Unlucky, the last thing you see is the steel fist of the Karossean war machine...</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="289">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="134" location="Capital City">
    <text>You try your best to sneak in without being seen — but there are too many enemies about. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="243">
        <text>If you have an enemy uniform and want to wear it for this trip.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="266">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="135" location="Unknown">
    <text>Quickly, you turn your robot. But you were seen.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="293">
        <text>If your robot's speed is Very Fast.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="362">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="136" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The enemy fighter swoops around you, its guns hammering. Your canopy cracks. From somewhere behind you, you hear explosions. Then all is darkness. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="137" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You are in the City of the Jungle. This is a relatively small city, a home for explorers, gatherers of valuable plants and lovers of the wilderness. Wild dinosaurs often walk the very streets of the City of the Jungle. What will you do here?</text>
    <revisitText>You are back in the City of the Jungle.</revisitText>
    <choices>
      <choice to="349">
        <text>Face the Karossean patrol.</text>
        <condition>context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="366">
        <text>Explore the city.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="170">
        <text>Explore the jungle.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="298">
        <text>Leave the city.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="138" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The Ape throws several large chunks of metal at you. Lose 2 ARMOUR points (if this reduces your ARMOUR to o, turn immediately to 61). When you attack the Ape, it flees. You look around the junkyard, but the only useful things you see are too heavy for you to move, and the junkyard equipment is out of order..</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="61">
        <text>if this reduces your ARMOUR to 0.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="110">
        <text>). When you attack the Ape, it flees. You look around the junkyard, but the only useful things you see are too heavy for you to move, and the junkyard equipment is out of order.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="139" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Test your Luck. If you are Lucky, you aim your valiant little robot right at the Pteranodon. A second before the crash, you bail out! Lose t STAMINA point for cuts and bruises. Your parachute brings you to earth not far from a small village. If you are Unlucky, you cannot bail out in time. You and your robot spiral together to a fiery doom. When your instruments tell you that you have penetrated to the heart Of the Storm, you take the precious flask Of Lavender Potion and unstopper it. Quickly, you pour it through the ejection lock. It diffuses in the air around you. You smile; you know the storm will quickly carry it to every part Of Thalos.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="13">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="140" location="Unknown">
    <text>When you land, the people of the City of Worship are already awake. No Karosseans are in sight. Your radio picks up scraps of chatter. everywhere, your people are reviving and driving Off the Karossean invaders. You have saved your people, and your adventure is over. You are a hero.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="141" location="Unknown">
    <text>A claw-like leaf reaches in through a crack in the armour. You scream and strike at it with your sword, but to no avail. A mere human cannot hope to stand against the appetite Of the Man-trap Plant! Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="142" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your mission is more important than this asinine robot. You will have to deal with it by force. GUARD ROBOT SKILL 8 STAMINA 10 Note that this robot is human-sized, and you fight it as though it were a human foe. You may Escape at any time by turning to 118.</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Guard Robot" skill="8" skillMax="8" stamina="10" staminaMax="10">
        <description>A human-sized guard robot blocking your way.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="48" escape="118" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="143" location="Unknown">
    <text>You enter the National Treasure House. Normally you would never be allowed inside— but now, who is to stop you? You feast your eyes on gold bars Of all sizes, sacks of coins and bags of jewels. But you see nothing that looks like a weapon. However, in the warehouse area is a cargo-handling robot. You may take it if you wish. If you have no robot right now, you will certainly take it! This machine looks like a gigantic crab, and is called a Cargo Crab. It has eight legs, plus two huge claws for lifting cargo. Its armoured back opens up to carry heavy loads. CARGO CRAB ARMOUR 12 SPEED Slow COMBAT BONUSO SPECIAL ABILITIES: The Cargo Crab can carry large quantities Of goods or equipment. If you take the Cargo Crab, you must leave your other robot (if any) at the Treasure House. Now.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="363">
        <text>Now.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="144" location="City of Storms">
    <text>You are in the City Of Storms. This beautiful metropolis is on the sea-coast, and is often the site of spectacular thunderstorms. Where would you like to go: The Weather Bureau? The coast? Another city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="260">
        <text>The Weather Bureau?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="335">
        <text>The coast?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="43">
        <text>Another city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="145" location="Capital City">
    <text>sentry is not fooled. He fires immediately. Lose 2 ARMOUR points and.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="27">
        <text>Lose 2 ARMOUR points and.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="146" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Hall Beta proves to be a long walk away, through great shadowed corridors. You soon realize that you are lost. Eventually you come to a curtained exhibitroom. The sign over the door reads 'Favours ot Fortune'. But inside, you hear strange sounds — like something large moving about.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="202">
        <text>If you enter.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="168">
        <text>If you go on past.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="147" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are leaving the College of War. Where will you go: The College of Medicine? The Thalian Museum? The Dinosaur Preserve? Another city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="54">
        <text>The College of Medicine?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="66">
        <text>The Thalian Museum? The Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="380">
        <text>Another city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="148" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="91">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="161">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="149" location="Capital City">
    <text>Suddenly, you find yourself outside the temple. Lose 1 LUCK point for your unwillingness to take chances. you may not visit this temple again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="150" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>What would you like to do now: Visit the College of Medicine? Visit the College of War? Visit the Thalian Museum? Leave the City Of Knowledge?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="54">
        <text>Visit the College of Medicine?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="277">
        <text>Visit the College of War?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>Visit the Thalian Museum?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="380">
        <text>Leave the City Of Knowledge?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="151" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You feel your robot tipping under you. A marshy spot! Instinctively, you put on a burst of speed to get past the danger.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="237">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="152" location="Unknown">
    <text>You move cautiously through the once busy streets. In the distance you see a pair of enemy robots striding along, but they take no notice of you. You reach the hospital safely.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="192">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="153" location="Capital City">
    <text>You go down a street of tall buildings and turn a comer. In front of you is a Karossean robot! But its back is turned to you. What will you do: Leave quietly? Attack it? Challenge it?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="290">
        <text>Leave quietly?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="311">
        <text>Attack it?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="108">
        <text>Challenge it?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="154" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>Lose 2 STAMINA points. Dazed and bleeding, you are pulled from the wreckage of your robot. 'This is the trouble-maker, all right!' you hear one Karossean say. You do not have time to use medikits right now! If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="241">
        <text>If you possess a Karossean uniform.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="89">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="155" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You examine the smashed robot. Inside, you see its pilot; he does not appear to be wounded. But as you reach a metal claw towards his bubble, he stabs at a control. His machine self-destructs! Your own robot is thrown back several metres and you are shaken up: lose 2 ARMOUR points and 2 STAMINA points.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="61">
        <text>If your ARMOUR has been reduced to o.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="65">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="156" location="Capital City">
    <text>The ground shakes, and from the shadows comes another enemy war machine to confront you. From within comes a radio transmission: Thalian! This is Minos! Now taste my wrath!' Your two robots hammer at each other. Around you the Karossean camp is going up in flames. You see a small fighter-robot smashed by a single stray shot. Then you can spare no attention for anything but the battle. The Supertank Minos is piloting is the biggest robot the Karosseans have. It looks like a vast, misshapen tank. A huge gun blazes in front; elsewhere are smaller weapons. Its arms are retracted for safety in the battle.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Supertank" frame="Unspecified" armor="16" armorMax="16" skill="12" skillMax="12" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow">
        <description>The biggest robot of the Karosseans. Piloted by Minos himself.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="354" lose="6" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="157" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The rusty lift clangs shut and begins to ascend. Higher and higher it goes. Then, with a shriek, the cable snaps. The lift descends again, much faster. When it stops, kilometres below the surface, your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="158" location="Capital City">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="242">
        <text>If you possess the Sword of State.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="214">
        <text>If you do not possess that sword.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="159" location="Capital City">
    <text>Behind you, your Other robot explodes. You dash into the nearest building and down into the cellar. To your surprise, the cellar is very large. In the centre rests a silvery machine with a large corkscrew at the nose. You jump in and close the hatch. The machine starts up. This Borer Robot was designed for travelling under the surface of the earth. It has no weapons or armour, and cannot be used in combat. As you tunnel into the earth, you hear the building collapsing overhead. All the better they will be sure they have killed you.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="338">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="160" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>As you approach the museum, you see smoke rising from in front of the building. A confused babble of Karossean voices comes over the radio. If you go elsewhere, but do not choose to return to the museum!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="184">
        <text>If you continue.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>If you go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="161" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You carefully examine the Robot Surgeon. A pair of wires appears to be crossed. But when you switch them, the machine comes alive and grabs you! It seems to want to remove your appendix! Lose 1 STAMINA point immediately! You must fight the berserk machine. ROBOT SURGEON SKILL 6 STAMINA 8 The room is so small that you cannot Escape.</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Robot Surgeon" skill="6" skillMax="6" stamina="8" staminaMax="8">
        <description>A malfunctioning robot surgeon trying to operate on you.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
    <choices>
      <choice to="126">
        <text>Look for information on sleeping sickness.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="210">
        <text>Leave the building.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="162" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Your robot crashes to the ground, destroyed. You hide in the wreckage until your assailant goes away. Lose 1 STAMINA point for cuts and bruises. Then you Start hiking towards the small village you see on the horizon.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="13">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="163" location="City of Storms">
    <text>In the Weather Bureau, you find banks of humming instruments. You also find a printout that explains the flags you saw outside. Apparently a huge storm is due to hit Thalos in a few hours. It will come ashore at the City of Worship, and die away as it rolls over the rest Of the land. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="213">
        <text>If you possess a flask of Potion.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="164" location="Capital City">
    <text>You wander about the Capitol Building until a flickering begins to warn you that the Cloak is running down. Quickly you head back to your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="165" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You are in the City of Pleasure. It is your country's vacation spot, where rich and poor alike come to partake of a thousand different amusements. What would you like to do: Visit the arcades? Visit the airfield? Leave the city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="288">
        <text>Visit the arcades?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="41">
        <text>Visit the airfield?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="131">
        <text>Leave the city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="166" location="City of Worship">
    <text>You are in the City of Worship. The whole of this metropolis is devoted to shrines, temples, churches, cemeteries and the like. It is always a quiet place, but you have never before seen it this quiet. Only the call of a sea-bird breaks the stillness. An uneasy thought occurs to you. If you are the only Thalian awake, then the attention of all the Powers must be focused on you personally. Your visit to the City of Worship might be rather... interesting. What would you like to do?</text>
    <revisitText>You are back in the City of Worship.</revisitText>
    <choices>
      <choice to="67">
        <text>Answer the Karossean challenge.</text>
        <condition>context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="49">
        <text>Visit one of the temples.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="227">
        <text>Fly over the city.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="244">
        <text>Go to another city.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="167" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>You have chosen a versatile but powerful humanoid robot, a Trouper XI. This is the standard Thalian combat robot. It has two forms: it can shape itself into a giant metal warrior, or into a sleek combat plane. TROOPER XI Human Form ARMOUR 12 SPEED Medium COMBAT BONUS +2 Plane Form ARMOUR 10 SPEED Very Fast COMBAT BONUS +2 SPECIAL ABILITIES: In human form, the Trouper XI carries a gun in one hand and a shield in the other. On an Attack Strength roll of 18 or better, even if the enemy hits it, the robot gets the shield in the way and takes no damage. In plane form, the robot has no special combat abilities. It takes one combat change forms. During that turn, the robot makes its normal combat roll, but if it wins, it does no damage to the foe - it just defends itself. The shield does not protect it on this turn. You may take one of these robots if you like (there are many here). Or,</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="376">
        <text>Take a Trouper XI and leave.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="247">
        <text>Take a tank robot instead.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Trouper XI" frame="Humanoid" armor="12" armorMax="12" speed="Average" speedMax="Average" combatBonus="2" combatBonusMax="2">
        <description>A versatile Thalian combat robot that can change between warrior and combat-plane forms.</description>
      </robot>
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="168" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>It takes one combat change forms. During that turn, the robot makes its normal combat roll, but if it wins, it does no damage to the foe — it just defends itself. The shield does not protect it on this 168 You continue on your way towards Hall Beta and the military exhibition. When you arrive, it proves to be ancient history. The strange sounds from the building are making you nervous. and you have no desire to read about catapults and other ancient devices. You go back to the main desk.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="169" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You must fight the enemy robots. There are two of them, both Tripod Robots. These speedy machines walk about on three legs; they have metal tentacle-arms that can carry guns or other devices. You recognize them as handling-machines belonging to the fuel plant. The Karosseans have taken them over as guard robots! You must fight them both at once. Each Tripod will have a separate attack on you in each Attack Round, but you must choose which of the two you will fight. Attack your chosen foe each round as in a normal battle. Against the other you must throw for your Attack Strength in the normal way, but even if your Attack Strength is greater, you will not wound it. You must just count this as though you have defended yourself from it. However, if its Attack Strength is greater, it will damage your robot in the usual way. SPECIAL ABILITIES: None.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="First Tripod" frame="Unspecified" armor="7" armorMax="7" skill="8" skillMax="8" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A captured fuel-plant handling machine converted into a guard robot.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" lose="336" />
      </monster>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Second Tripod" frame="Unspecified" armor="7" armorMax="7" skill="10" skillMax="10" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A captured fuel-plant handling machine converted into a guard robot.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="30" lose="336" escape="293" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="170" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>How are you equipped for this trip: A flying robot? A non-flying robot? No robot at all?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="285">
        <text>A flying robot?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="356">
        <text>A non-flying robot?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="64">
        <text>No robot at all?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="171" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>If you have already opened this building, turn immediately to 231. Otherwise, keep reading. You walk around the barn-like building and examine it. The walls are built of heavy metal, and the only door you can find is huge. A sign on the door reads, 'DANGER! KEEP OUT!' What will you do:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="231">
        <text>If you have already opened this building.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="212">
        <text>Open the door?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Go to the Administrative Building (if you have not already done so)?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="129">
        <text>Get in your robot and cross the electro-fence?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="172" location="Unknown">
    <text>You're spotted! One Of them raises a huge weapon and points it at you. 'What's the password?' it broadcasts. What will you say: 'Seven'? 'Twooh-three'? 'Eighty-eight'?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="262">
        <text>'Seven'?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="203">
        <text>'Twooh-three'?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="88">
        <text>'Eighty-eight'?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="173" location="Capital City">
    <text>You give one of the passwords you have learned. But it is of no use. Soon, you are chained to a wall, awaiting the pleasure of Minos. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="174" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You cautiously search through the building. Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="259">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="114">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="175" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>The computer guides you to the main building Of the City of the Guardians. You get out of your robot to investigate. Unfortunately, you soon learn that 'Level Zero' means your security clearance is very low. The Guardian Computer cannot or Will not give you full access to the secrets of the base. However, it does seem willing to let you exchange your current robot for a high-powered war robot. (If you do so, make a note of the fact that your old robot remains here.) Will you select a slow, powerful tank robot, or a speedy shape-changing humanoid/plane robot?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="247">
        <text>) Will you select a slow, powerful tank robot (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="167">
        <text>), or a speedy shape-changing humanoid/plane robot (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="376">
        <text>)? If you prefer to keep your current robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="176" location="Capital City">
    <text>You pop out of the doomed flyer a second before it explodes. The enemy robots shoot past, without seeing you. You feel a tug on your harness — and over you spread the wings of a parasail! You find you can guide it as you please.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="205">
        <text>If you steer for the heart of the enemy encampment, where a crowd of men are looking up at you.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="226">
        <text>If you steer away and try to lose yourself in the buildings.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="177" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Your trick is successful. The enemy pilot sees your uniform and lets you go without asking for the password. He ignores you as you go past him peacefully.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="65">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="178" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The tunnel seems to descend for ever. You feel fatigued. Lose 1 STAMINA point. Eventually, it reaches a landing. You take the stairway up.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="294">
        <text>Take the stairway up.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="179" location="City of Storms">
    <text>An hour into your trip, a powerful storrn strikes. Otherwise, you ride out the storm safely on the ground and then resume your journey.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="280">
        <text>If your robot is a flying type.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>Otherwise, you ride out the storm safely on the ground and then resume your journey.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="180" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Just as you are about ready to give up, you stumble across an interesting book on the duelling customs of the Karosseans. Apparently the ancient Karos­ seans would settle a tribal dispute by choosing champions - one from each tribe - instead of allow­ing a battle between the whole tribes. The reference number of the book is 111.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="224">
        <text>Return to the front desk.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <items>
      <item tag="Karossean Book Reference" name="Karossean Book Reference" icon="karossean_book_reference.png">
        <description>'..the ancient Karosseans would settle a tribal dispute by choosing champions..'.</description>
      </item>
    </items>
  </block>
  <block id="181" location="Unknown">
    <text>Roll two dice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="28">
        <text>If the result is less than or equal to your SKILL.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="318">
        <text>If the result is greater than your SKILL.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="182" location="City of Industry">
    <text>NO ADMITTANCE 182 When you leave the lift on the third floor, you immediately spy a man-sized Guard Robot standing in the hallway. 'Sorry. No admittance,' squawks its mechanical voice. What Will you do: Try to reason with the robot? Attack the robot? Go to another floor?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="295">
        <text>Try to reason with the robot?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="142">
        <text>Attack the robot?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>Go to another floor?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="183" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You push the 'Eject' button. To your surprise, your cockpit separates and takes Off on its own! A second later, the rest of your robot explodes. Seeing the explosion, the Wasp loops away and disappears. You take stock of your new craft: the cockpit of your robot has grown stubby wings and short grasping arms. It is a tiny flying robot, just big enough to hold, you—but enough to get you to your destination. ESCAPE ROBOT ARMOURI SPEED Very Fast COMBAT BONUSO.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>ESCAPE ROBOT ARMOURI SPEED Very Fast COMBAT BONUSO.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="184" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You continue towards the museum. When you arrive, you see a strange sight! Two Karossean utility robots are lying wrecked in front of the building. Several Karossean soldiers are also sprawled unmoving. A huge, gleaming, metal Tyrannosaurus is walking in jerky circles in front Of the museum. You recognize it as the robot dinosaur that was part of the museum's prize exhibit. The Karosseans must have meddled and activated it! You are tempted to leave it alone to harass the foe. On the other hand, it is likely to cause damage to the buildings and your sleeping countrymen as well. If you leave it alone and go elsewhere, but do not choose to return to the museum!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="207">
        <text>If you attack the Robot Tyrannosaurus.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>If you leave it alone and go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="185" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Soon, you spot a sign saying 'SURGERY'. Following it, you see a robot surgeon over a table. But it is marked 'OUT OF ORDER'.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="148">
        <text>If you will try to find what is wrong and repair it.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="126">
        <text>If you leave it alone and look for information on sleeping sickness.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="186" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Not long ago you passed a village. There might be something useful there.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="13">
        <text>If you want to check.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>If you want to press on to the City of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="187" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have not gone far before you have to pass through a narrow gate that leads into the outer part of the stadium. There, you are challenged by a group Of robots. 'Eighty-eight!' comes the word. If you know the countersign, that number. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="50">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="188" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your path narrows; the ground underfoot seems marshy. Roll two dice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="151">
        <text>If the result is less than or equal to your SKILL forrobot control.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="312">
        <text>If the result is greater than your SKI LL.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="189" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Everything seems to be as you left it. The Karosseans have no interest in this area, and no desire to get any closer to the monsters than they have to! What Will you do: Leave your robot and go to the Administrative Building? Leave your robot and go to the other building? Stay in your robot and cross the electro-fence? Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Leave your robot and go to the Administrative Building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="171">
        <text>Leave your robot and go to the other building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="129">
        <text>Stay in your robot and cross the electro-fence?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="190" location="Capital City">
    <text>Test your Luck. If you are Lucky, you can get behind the case and remove the sword without either guard being the wiser. You hide it under your Cloak and leave the Capitol Building. If you are Unlucky, one of the guards notices the sword seemingly hanging in mid-air. and fight.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="296">
        <text>You hide it under your Cloak and leave the Capitol Building (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="215">
        <text>). If you are Unlucky, one of the guards notices the sword seemingly hanging in mid-air.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="191" location="Unknown">
    <text>If you had a robot, lose STAMINA point as you are thrown from the wreckage. If you are Still alive, you flee on foot as the Nothosaurus demolishes your robot. If you have not already explored the south Of the city, you may do so. Otherwise, you flee into the jungle.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="225">
        <text>If you have not already explored the south Of the city, you may do so (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="64">
        <text>). Otherwise, you flee into the jungle (.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="192" location="Capital City">
    <text>You arrive safely at the Capital City hospital. You can see that you will have to be careful; you hear voices echoing through the halls. If you possess the Cloak of Invisibility and have not used it, you may use it now.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="29">
        <text>If you possess the Cloak of Invisibility and have not used it, you may use it now (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="74">
        <text>). If you have already used it, do not have it, or simply choose not to use it now.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="193" location="Capital City">
    <text>You enter the huge black building. You feel a tremor of uncertainty. As usual, you see steepers everywhere — but are they really asleep? They look dead! You lift the wrist Of the nearest one and check for a pulse. You feel nothing! You look wildly around you, but see nothing. Yet you are terrified. Screaming, you run back outside into the sunlight. When you escape from the temple, the irrational fear vanishes as quickly as it came. But you are still shaking. Reduce your SKILL by t. Otherwise, return.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="327">
        <text>If you get hold of yourself and re-enter the grim temple.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="166">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="194" location="Capital City">
    <text>The other robot's control bubble springs open, and out flies the Karossean soldier who was piloting it! His unfamiliarity with the controls was fatal: he hit the ejection lever by mistake! He falls under the wheels of his own machine and is lost. If you wish, you can take the Construction Robot instead of your current robot. Its COMBAT BONUS is o. Whether or not you take it, ask something else.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Whether or not you take it.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="195" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Al 195 At the outskirts of the city, you find a huge robot junkyard. Otherwise, keep reading. As far as the eye can see, scrapped and damaged robots and pieces of robots are standing, sitting and lying on the ground. But out Of the corner Of your eye, you see motion. Something seems to be watching you from behind a pile of scrap! If you leave, Ito.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="82">
        <text>If you have been here before.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="370">
        <text>Otherwise, keep reading. As far as the eye can see, scrapped and damaged robots and pieces of robots are standing, sitting and lying on the ground. But out Of the corner Of your eye, you see motion. Something seems to be watching you from behind a pile of scrap! If you investigate the junkyard.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="196" location="City of Storms">
    <text>You soon outdistance the stampeding dinosaurs. You Return to the city.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="197" location="Unknown">
    <text>tf you have already been challenged by Karossean 197 soldiers using a number as a password, and you remember that number, that reference.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="236">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="198" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Just in time, you realize that the lobby is full of Guard Robots like the one you fought before. You quickly return to your robot and leave the area of the Centre.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="206">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="199" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Your gamble is successful. The enemy pilot has no reason to believe that any Thalians are awake, so he assumes you must be a friend. He ignores you as you go past him peacefully.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="65">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="200" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>Becaåse of the practice you got in the arcade game, you know how to handle this robot properly.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="378">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="201" location="Capital City">
    <text>You watch carefully. When your chance comes, you strike! The tyrant falls dead! You attack the other nearby officers. With your Cloak of Invisibility, you are like an avenging demon among them. But there are dozens Of them, and they are brave fighterS. Eventually, though they can see only your blade, they pull you down by sheer numbers. Your adventure is over. You destroyed the tyrant, but your land is still enslaved. You have failed but it was a glorious failure!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="202" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>To your relief, the sounds you heard were merely the snoring of a very fat man, asleep in a chair. The room is dedicated to exhibits having todo with good and bad luck. You pause to look around. Then your eye is drawn by a display-case at the far end of the room. It must be important— there were two guards beside it! They are still there, fast asleep. The case contains a jewelled necklace, rather crudely made. But according to the sign on the case, it is a genuine, scientifically proven good-luck charm. This looks as though it might be worth borrowing! You open the case and take the Luck Amulet. Somewhere, you hear an alarm gooff, soyou hurry away. But the charm is real. Increase your L u score (and your Initial LUCK) by 1. You go on towards Hall Beta.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="168">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="203" location="Unknown">
    <text>'Wrong, Thalian!' comes the enemy voice. Then both robots attack. Amazingly, one misses! Still, you lose 2 ARMOUR points.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="281">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="204" location="Capital City">
    <text>Why bother, indeed? There seems to be no reason to do anything, and every reason to do nothing. After a while you leave the temple, since nothing is there. When you see the sun again, some of your energy comes back. But you still feel drained. Reduce your STA MI N A to 4, if it was higher than 4. O</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="205" location="Capital City">
    <text>You steer right for the crowd. Amazingly, no one attacks you! You make a creditable landing in the middle of a circle of gaudily uniformed Karosseans. You know that your only chance now is to put on as good a show as possible. If you know something that might help you now, the reference number that came with that information. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="228">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="206" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You are back in your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>Explore elsewhere in the City of Industry.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="309">
        <text>Go to another city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="207" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You decide to fight. The Robot Tyrannosaurus is an intricate device, shaped just like a Tyrannosaurus, but all gears and metal — and tougher than a real dinosaur. It has no pilot, but runs on a pre-set (and very destructive) program.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Robot Tyrannosaurus" frame="Unspecified" armor="11" armorMax="11" skill="10" skillMax="10" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>An intricated device shaped like a Tyrannosaurus but all gears and metal.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="230" lose="255" escape="52" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="208" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>It looks like a gigantic snake! But as you approach, you see it is actually a robot, a Serpent VII. This unit was designed to track and hunt dinosaurs. It has no legs; its gripper-arms fold against the body when not in use. Its shape gives it good mobility in the jungle. SERPENT VII ARMOUR 9 SPEED Fast in jungle; Medium elsewhere COMBAT BONUS +1 SPECIAL ABILITIES: Any time the Serpent's Attack Roll is 16 or better, it can coil around its foe. From then on, it automatically does 1 extra point of damage each combat round, regardless of who wins, until it flees or one combatant is destroyed. This does not apply to flying foes. If you like, you can take the Serpent VII. If you already have a robot, make a note of the fact: that robot will be here should you return. If you have not already explored to the north, you may do so by turning to 16. Or you may leave off exploring the city and.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="16">
        <text>Explore to the north.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>Leave off exploring the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Serpent VII" frame="Unspecified" armor="9" armorMax="9" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast" combatBonus="1" combatBonusMax="1">
        <description>A snake-like dinosaur-hunting robot with good jungle mobility.</description>
      </robot>
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="209" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You set a course for the City of Industry, a place of great factories and machinery. There, you reason, you might find a robot or invention that would give you an advantage over the invaders.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>Keep flying to the city.</text>
        <condition>context.Robot is not null &amp;&amp; context.Robot.Abilities.Any(a =&gt; a.Name == "Flying")</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="39">
        <text>Keep walking to the city.</text>
        <condition>context.Robot is not null &amp;&amp; !context.Robot.Abilities.Any(a =&gt; a.Name == "Flying")</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="210" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You decide to leave the College of Medicine. You climb back into your trusty robot, Where will you go now:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="277">
        <text>To the College of War.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>To the Thalian Museum.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="66">
        <text>To the Dinosaur Preserve.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="390">
        <text>Out of the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="211" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You quickly pass the flower in through a port. You unstopper your flask of Potion and drop the flower in. The Potion changes colour to lavender. But, as you put the Lavender Potion safely away, you hear a scratching noise from outside.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="248">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="212" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You have a hunch that the barn-like building may contain something of importance. But the door is far too heavy for you to budge. Getting back into your robot, you use its strength to slide open the huge door. Inside you see more robots!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="9">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="213" location="City of Storms">
    <text>You realize that this may be just the chance you have been looking for! If you released your Potion into the heart of the storm, it would soon be distributed all over Thalos. But to do this, you will require a flying robot, and you will have to get to the City of Worship.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="214" location="Capital City">
    <text>Minos is a huge, burly man with a curling black beard. His uniform is gold-encrusted and ornate. He studies you with amusement. 'Duel you?' he says. 'Why should I duel you, Thalian vermin?' 'I'm the only Thalian awake!' you reply. 'You Juve to duel me! I demand it!' Around Minos, the other officers mutter. Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="314">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="297">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="215" location="Capital City">
    <text>The guards are not prepared to fight an invisible opponent. Normally crack troops, their SKILL is low for this fight because of their surprise. Fight them one at a time. Because of your Cloak, you can Escape, if need be, without taking a wound.</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="First Guard" skill="5" skillMax="5" stamina="8" staminaMax="8">
        <description>A surprised Karossean guard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Second Guard" skill="4" skillMax="4" stamina="9" staminaMax="9">
        <description>A surprised Karossean guard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="334" escape="296" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="216" location="Capital City">
    <text>Lose LUCK point for cowardice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="217" location="City of Worship">
    <text>Fight them as a single enemy:</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Mini-Robots" frame="Unspecified" armor="9" armorMax="9" skill="10" skillMax="10" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A swarm of small robots.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="166" escape="278" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="218" location="City of Worship">
    <text>You realize that you have stumbled on to a topsecret military base. Frantically, you tell the computer what has happened. Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="337">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="2">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="219" location="Capital City">
    <text>If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="303">
        <text>If you are wearing a Karossean uniform.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="11">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="220" location="Unknown">
    <text>Since your robot is not designed for cargo, you can carry only a small amount of gold.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="287">
        <text>If you want to load up what you can.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="30">
        <text>If you leave empty-handed.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="221" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You sit down in the seat. Instantly, you find your self at the controls of a sleek fighter — the experimental Wasp 200! For twenty minutes you seem to fly through the skies, pursuing enemy robots. Then a timer buzzes and you find yourself back at the Arcade. In front of you, a screen is blinking 'Advanced Game Ready!' You have earned extra time.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="324">
        <text>If you decide to play the extra time.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="288">
        <text>If you leave this game.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="222" location="Capital City">
    <text>pass, friend!' the sentry robot transmits. 'But don't go past the next ring. That's officer country.'</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="76">
        <text>' If you continue in your robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="32">
        <text>If you enter on foot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="223" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>From within his robot, the Karossean sentry challenges you. Your reply does not satisfy him. You must fight!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="78">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="224" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You leave the military display and take a short cut through a hallway overlooking a huge gallery. As you look down, you are surprised to see devasta­tion! A huge area of exhibits has been demolished. Two black-clad Karossean soldiers are lying there, dead or wounded, and a trail of devastation leads right through a huge hole in the wall. You hear shouts from below.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="374">
        <text>Go down and investigate.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="1014">
        <text>Go back to the information desk.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="225" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You go south through the deserted city. Small lizards scuttle about. You remember that you are not far from the edge of the jungle here. Ahead you see a long, gleaming shape, like a huge length of mottled pipe. What will you do: Investigate it? Turn around and search the north (if you have not done so already)? Abandon your city exploration?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="208">
        <text>Investigate it?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="16">
        <text>Turn around and search the north (if you have not done so already)?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>Abandon your city exploration?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="226" location="Capital City">
    <text>You steer towards an area of wooded parkland, hoping to escape. But they are tracking you. When you land, you are surrounded almost before you can remove your harness, and taken off to prison. A good try — but not good enough. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="227" location="City of Worship">
    <text>A violent storm is coming from over the ocean; it will strike land in minutes.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="12">
        <text>If you fly into the storm.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="244">
        <text>If you fly inland, away from the storm and the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="228" location="Capital City">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="267">
        <text>If you try to bluff your way out of this situation.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="283">
        <text>If you try to fight your way past.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="229" location="City of Industry">
    <text>On the tenth floor, you find an incredible confusion Of cubbyholes, and nothing that looks like a robot or device. There are tall bookshelves everywhere, and more books on the floor and the desks.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="360">
        <text>If you continue to investigate.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>If you return to the lobby.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="230" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You have defeated your strange foe. It falls, a smoking wreck. Regain 2 LVCX points for defending your people from this unusual menace. You know the battle will soon draw Karossean attention, and you had better not come back here. You leave; you may not Return to the museum again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="231" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The barn-like building where you found the robots is also as you left it. Your old robot is there— you may take it back if you like. Or you may get another Super-Cowboy Robot. What will you do now?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="85">
        <text>Walk over to the Administrative Building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="129">
        <text>Get in your robot and cross the electro-fence?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Leave the Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="232" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>As you walk down the corridors of the hospital, you hear a strange squeaking and rustling noise coming from all around you. You see by the signs that you are in the Research Lab section. The noise does not sound human - but it is certainly no robot! You feel better with your sword in hand. You step through a pair of double doors, into a room full of large wire cages. You see that some are opened. Then you realize what the sounds were. The hospital's experimental animals have escaped... and they are hungry! You run, but your way is blocked. You are facing three Giant Lizards! Backing into the corner of the room, you may fight them one at a time, in order. You cannot try to Escape until you have slain the first two.</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="First Giant Lizard" stamina="4" staminaMax="4" skill="7" skillMax="7">
        <description>A hungry escaped laboratory lizard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Second Giant Lizard" stamina="6" staminaMax="6" skill="6" skillMax="6">
        <description>A hungry escaped laboratory lizard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Third Giant Lizard" stamina="5" staminaMax="5" skill="7" skillMax="7">
        <description>A hungry escaped laboratory lizard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="254" escape="254" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="233" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="351">
        <text>If your robot is a humanoid type.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="318">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="234" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You speak calmly to the Ape, and it begins to caper and grunt. It is a pet, kept to help around the yard! You look around the junkyard, but the only useful things you see are too heavy for you to move, and the junkyard equipment is out of order. Then the Ape, which has been watching you, lends a hand. Deftly, it takes apart the robot you have been studying. and carries the parts as you indicate. With the help of the Ape, you may repair up to 4 ARMOUR points on your robot, if that many had been lost.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="110">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="235" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Your robot is scratched and dented, but you have won. Lose 1 ST A M t N A point for the bruises you took when the monster knocked your robot over. You continue on your way towards the City of Industry.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="236" location="Unknown">
    <text>Over the radio comes a challenge: 'Eighty-eight!' If you know the countersign that is required for that password, the number of the countersign.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="389">
        <text>If you do not know the proper response.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="237" location="Unknown">
    <text>You continue through the jungle. It is hard going: hidden pits and logs take their toll on your robot. Reduce its ARMOUR by 2. (If this reduces its ARMOUR to o or less, leave its ARMOUR at t.) Eventually, the city comes into view; you are relieved! But, as you enter it, you twice see flytng Karossean robots patrolling overhead. Each time you hold your own robot motionless and they overlook you. But you realize that this city is no longer safe; there are Karosseans everywhere.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="45">
        <text>If you came to this city in another robot and you would like to switch back to it.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="298">
        <text>If you stay in your current robot to leave the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="238" location="Unknown">
    <text>You eject from the battered robot and run for your life. Test your Luck. If you are Lucky, you evade pursuit: (without your robot!). If you are Unlucky, your adventure ends here in capture and defeat.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="239" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You attack the Iguanodon that is blocking your way. This plant-eating dinosaur walks on two legs. It is tough and heavy-set, and its spiky 'thumbs' are good weapons.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Iguanodon" frame="Dinosaur" armor="5" armorMax="5" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A tough and heavy-set plant eating dinosaur.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="137" lose="306" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="240" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The tunnel winds until you have lost all sense Of direction. Then it forks. One fork seems to go up; the other turns downward.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="72">
        <text>If you go up.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="15">
        <text>If you go down.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="241" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>Your captors do not even discuss what to do with you; they stand you against a wall and shoot you as a spy. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="242" location="Capital City">
    <text>Minos is a huge, burly man with a curling black beard. His uniform is gold-encrusted and ornate. He studies you with amusement. 'Duel you?' he says. 'Why should I duel you, Thalian vermin?' 'I'm the only Thalian awake!' you reply. 'And I have the Sword of State! That makes me the representative Of all Thalos! You have to duel me!' Around Minos, the other officers mutter. 'He's right,' says one. 'It's the law,' you hear another say. Others agree with them. Minos frowns angrily. Then he laughs. 'Very well, since you insist!' he says. 'We will fight. Right now!' The Sword of State is returned to you. You may now fight Minos him self!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="330">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="243" location="Capital City">
    <text>With the uniform, you try to bluff your way in. But soon a beribboned officer calls to you, 'Sergeant! Over here!' You have no hope Of bluffing it out. You dash around a corner, rip the uniform off and keep tunning. By the time a patrol rounds the corner, you are across the street, feigning sleep. But you will not be able to enter the Capitol Building. Lose 1 point of STAMINA. You return to your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="244" location="City of Worship">
    <text>You are leaving the City of Worship. Where would you like to go: The Capital City? The City Of Knowledge? The City of Storms?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>The Capital City?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>The City Of Knowledge?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>The City of Storms?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="245" location="Capital City">
    <text>You are blasted out of the sky. Your adventure ends here.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="246" location="Unknown">
    <text>As you jet through the water, you see a huge shadow swimming to intercept you. It is a Tylosaurus, one of the most feared of marine dinosaurs. This monster looks like a cross between a huge, toothy lizard and a shark; it has finny paddles instead of legs. It normally lives on fish, but is willing to try a robot for variety!</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Tylosaurus" frame="Dinosaur" armor="9" armorMax="9" skill="10" skillMax="10" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A cross between a huge, toothy lizard and a shark.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="101" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="247" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>You have chosen a powerful Robotank. This fearsome war machine looks like a human from the waist up. From the waist down, it is a huge tank, with terrible twin guns. It is one of the few battleline machines your land possesses. ROBOTANK ARMOUR 18 SPEED Slow COMBAT BONUS +2 SPECIAL ABILITIES: The Robotank contains a special Sonic Gun in one hand. It cannot be used by any other robot. It may be fired once per combat turn, in addition to the Robotank's regular attack. However, it may be used only three times in all; then it is useless. When fired, the Sonic Gun is instantly deadly to unprotected humans. Against a robot, roll one die to see how many ARMOUR points the target loses. Against a dinosaur, roll two dice to see how many ARMOUR points the target loses. There are three of these robots here. You may take one and leave, or, if you prefer, you may to take a faster robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="376">
        <text>Take a Robotank and leave.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="167">
        <text>Take a faster robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Robotank" frame="Humanoid" armor="18" armorMax="18" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow" combatBonus="2" combatBonusMax="2">
        <description>A powerful battleline machine with terrible twin guns and a Sonic Gun.</description>
      </robot>
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="248" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>The spiky leaves reach towards you, and the flower stalk pulls back to show a fanged mouth. The plant is hungry! MAN-TRAP PLANT ARMOUR 8 SPEED see below SKILL 9 Since the Man-trap Plant has caught hold of you before the battle starts, differences in Speed do not matter. You cannot Escape.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Man-trap Plant" frame="Unspecified" armor="8" armorMax="8" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Static" speedMax="Static">
        <description>A hungry plant whose spiky leaves have caught hold of your robot.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="97" lose="141" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="249" location="Capital City">
    <text>You decide to visit the Temple Of Nothingness. You have never been there before, and you have no idea what to expect. When you arrive, you see the usual sprawled forms on the sidewalk in front. Several were carrying signs and placards. Were they protes tors? You look at a sign; it reads, 'Nothing is wrong. If you would rather not get involved with this strange bit of business, you may return.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>If you would rather not get involved with this strange bit of business, you may.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="123">
        <text>If you want to go inside.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="250" location="Unknown">
    <text>You wave to the robot and start to leave, but as you do, alarms go off and lights flash. 'I'm very sorry,' says the robot, 'but museum property has been removed without authorization. You cannot leave.' Its metal arms reach out towards you. Roll two dice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="272">
        <text>If the number you roll is less than or equal to your SKILL.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="294">
        <text>Otherv.'ise.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="251" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You have returned to the Robot Experimental Cene tre. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="198">
        <text>If you acquired the Seeker Missile on a previous visit.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="252" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You soar over the jungle of the Dinosaur Preserve, but see nothing of interest. You do not know what you expected to find out here, anyway! You decide to leave.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="253" location="Capital City">
    <text>You demand the right, as a representative Of your people, to duel Minos. The officer in charge shakes his head. 'Search him!' he orders his men. Your heart sinks. You are stripped of all your Possessions (including medikits). But then the sentries take you directly to Minos himself.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="158">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="254" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Near by you hear more squeaking and shuffling. There were many more than three opened cages in the lab.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="276">
        <text>Search through the lab.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="210">
        <text>Leave the College of Medicine.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="255" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Your robot falls, torn by the shining steel teeth Of the mechanical enemy. Lose 2 STAMINA points. As soon as your robot Stops moving, your foe loses interest and goes tramping away. When it is gone, you investigate your surroundings. You find that one of the wrecked Karossean robots is still just usable. You get in and check it out. It is a general purpose Karossean robot, humanoid in shape. It has been badly battered, so your COMBAT BON us is negative while you are in it. UTILITY ROBOT ARMOUR 4 SPEED Slow COMBATBONUS —2 SPECIAL ABILITIES: None Your only thought is to get away as quickly as possible. You know that your unsuccessful battle will soon draw Karossean attention, and you had better not come back here. You leave; you may not return to the museum again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="63">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="256" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The book gives you the location of the City Of the Guardians, the secret base that is the headquarters Of the army Of Thalos. The map reference is 22. Make a note of this number. Substitute it for 'XX' when you are given the option to visit the City of the Guardians. You may find another use for the map reference, as well. For now, of course, you must deal with the Karosseans outside the building you are in!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="368">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="257" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You try the advanced game... but itis far too hard for you. Over and over you are shot down. When your time is up, you emerge, shaking. That machine was too realistic! Lose point of STAMINA.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="288">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="258" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You wave to the robot and start to leave, but as you do, alarms go off and lights flash. 'I'm very sorry,' says the robot, 'but museum property has been removed without authorization. You cannot leave.' Its metal arms reach out towards you. Roll two dice.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="282">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="391">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="259" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You spy an open closet in an adjoining room. Inside you can see a medikit! You investigate; sure enough, the rest of your Possessions are here! You hastily collect them all and escape through a convenient window. e'</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="69">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="260" location="City of Storms">
    <text>Flying over the Weather Bureau are the two red flags that you know mean 'STORM WARNING!' Parked outside the building you see another robot, a Walker Robot. Designed primarily for travel, this robot has four jointed legs that carry it swiftly over any terrain. WALKER ROBOT ARMOUR 6 SPEED Fast COMBAT BONUS SPECIAL ABILITIES: None If you like, you may exchange this robot for your own. If you come back to this spot after exchanging, your own robot may still be here; make a note that this is where you are leaving it.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="163">
        <text>If you go inside the Weather Bureau.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>If you go on past.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="261" location="Capital City">
    <text>You turn aside and leave your own robot in order to examine this one. It is low-slung and seems spiky. You see that it is bristling with weapons, which is what gives the Hedgehog Robot its name. It was designed for air defence against flying dinosaurs, but it is equally effective against flying robots. HEDGEHOG ROBOT ARMOUR 8 SPEED Slow COüBAT BONUS O or +3 SPECIAL ABILITIES: Against flying foes, the Hedgehog has a COMBAT BONUS of +3, which more than cancels out its disadvantage in speed. If you like, you may exchange your present robot for this one. If you do so, make a note that your old robot is now parked here instead of the Hedgehog.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="57">
        <text>If you go on towards the Temple of Fear.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>If you return the way you came.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="262" location="Unknown">
    <text>There is a brief buzz of conversation between your enemies. Your answer seems to have confused them.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="281">
        <text>If you decide to attack immediately.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="203">
        <text>If you stand your ground without attacking.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="263" location="Unknown">
    <text>It is a large Crawler Robot. The crew, of course, is asleep, and you do not want to take their robot and leave them to the jungle. But within the robot is an interesting piece of equipment, like nothing you have ever seen. Reading the Crawler pilot's orders, you see the following: experimental Tangler Field works on flying machines — but not always. Your orders are to test it against flying dinosaurs immediately.' Beneath this is written, in large red letters, 'NO GOOD!' You may add the Tangler Field to your Possessions and continue.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="73">
        <text>If you explore the other path of the jungle.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>If you want to go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="264" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your attack catches the enemy by surprise. but you automatically win the first combat round without rolling!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="27">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="265" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You are in the City of Industry. Normally, it is busy and bustling, but now you see no life anywhere. Everyone is asleep... everyone but you. Where will you go in your quest for usefull artefacts:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="105">
        <text>The Fuel Refining Plant.</text>
        <condition>context.Robot is not null &amp;&amp; context.Robot.Abilities.Any(a =&gt; a.Name == "Flying")</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="25">
        <text>The Robot Experimental Centre.</text>
        <condition>context.Robot is not null &amp;&amp; !context.Robot.Abilities.Any(a =&gt; a.Name == "Flying")</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="127">
        <text>The tunnels underneath the city.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="34">
        <text>Just explore.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="309">
        <text>Leave the city.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="266" location="Capital City">
    <text>The building is crawling with Karosseans. There is no point in even thinking about entering. You return to your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="267" location="Capital City">
    <text>'I've got an important message for Minos himself!' you shout. 'You've got to let me through!' But your bluff does notwork. They drag you away and throw you into the slave-pits. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="268" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>It is a complete book of instructions on handling all types of enemy combat robots! You laugh, thinking of the surprise you can now give the Karosseans, if you get the chance.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="368">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="269" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Which button will you press: Green? Red? Blue?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="369">
        <text>Green?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="157">
        <text>Red?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="44">
        <text>Blue?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="270" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are shaken up; lose STAMINA point. Because Of the narrow jungle trails, your robot takes 3 points Of damage as it escapes. Otherwise, you flee the jungle:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="310">
        <text>If this is enough to bring its ARMOUR to 0.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="271" location="Unknown">
    <text>Well, this is war. You circle behind the hapless sentry — then rush him. Your sword swings silently and he is dead.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="143">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="272" location="Unknown">
    <text>You dodge underneath the mechanical arms with which it is hying to Stop you, and through the door. You quickly climb into the control seat of your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="396">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="273" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You find nothing else of interest in the shop. As you leave, the hammering noise continues behind you. The repair shop is awake, even if its masters are asleep.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="110">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="274" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="341">
        <text>If you are flying.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="5">
        <text>If you are travelling on the ground.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="275" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your battle has caused great confusion. Stray shots are wreaking havoc among the Karosseans and their lesser robots. But now a group of sleek fighter-craft swoop out of the sky to challenge you.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="301">
        <text>Use the Tangler Field.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="326">
        <text>Do not use the Tangler Field.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="276" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>This is a fatal error. Minutes later, you are trapped in a dead-end corridor by dozens of hunger-maddened laboratory animals, many of which are mutations - a most embarrassing end for a hero...</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="277" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The College of War is easy to find; it is a huge five-sided building built all of brick. If you have not been here before, keep reading. A robot of unfamiliar design is standing in front of the building. You recognize it as a Karossean military robot. What will you do: Attack immediately? Try to pass as one of the invaders? Leave before you are noticed?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="332">
        <text>If you have been here before.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="46">
        <text>Attack immediately?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="87">
        <text>Try to pass as one of the invaders?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="147">
        <text>Leave before you are noticed?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="278" location="City of Worship">
    <text>What will you do now: Fly into the storm (if you have a flying robot)? Leave the city, travelling on the ground? Explore the temples?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="12">
        <text>Fly into the storm (if you have a flying robot)?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="244">
        <text>Leave the city, travelling on the ground?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="49">
        <text>Explore the temples?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="279" location="Unknown">
    <text>Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="191">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="121">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="280" location="City of Storms">
    <text>Roll one die.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="122">
        <text>If you roll 1 or 2.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>If you roll 3, 4, 5 or 6.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="281" location="Capital City">
    <text>Fight the two enemy Myrmidon robots, one at a time. The Myrmidon is the standard Karossean combat robot. It has two forms - humanoid and fighter-plane. These are in humanoid form and will not try to change during the battle. SPECIAL ABILITIES: None in this combat.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="First Myrmidon" frame="Unspecified" armor="10" armorMax="10" skill="10" skillMax="10" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A Karossean Myrmidon in humanoid form.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" lose="238" />
      </monster>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Second Myrmidon" frame="Unspecified" armor="12" armorMax="12" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A Karossean Myrmidon in humanoid form.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="192" lose="238" escape="305" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="282" location="City of Industry">
    <text>While the Tyrannosaurus is tearing up the robot's torso, you dodge out of the cockpit, grab your backpack with your supplies and run into the shel ter of the boulders. Lose 3 STAMINA points for your injuries. You carefully depart, and gradually the sounds of roaring and destruction fade into the distance.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="367">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="283" location="Capital City">
    <text>You fight bravely, but there is no way you could possibly prevail against such numbers. Though you take several invaders with you, you are slain.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="284" location="City of Storms">
    <text>Flying over the sea-coast, you see nothing of interest except a huge herd of dinosaurs. They are clustered around something, but you cannot make out what it is. If you return to the city, and make another choice. If your robot can change shape to a land-going form, you may Jand and investigate the sea-coast. You realize that a flying robot is the wrong type for jungle exploration. What will you do:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>If you return to the city.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="8">
        <text>and make another choice. If your robot can change shape to a land-going form, you may Jand and investigate the sea-coast.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="285" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>Transform your robot into a walking shape (if you can) and enter the jungle? Leave the city? Explore the city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="356">
        <text>Transform your robot into a walking shape (if you can) and enter the jungle?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="298">
        <text>Leave the city?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="366">
        <text>Explore the city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="286" location="City of Worship">
    <text>'Then face your foe!' comes the answer. In front of you appears a Karossean soldier, armed like yourself. You must fight him. SOLDIER SKILL 10 STAMINA 10</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Soldier" skill="10" skillMax="10" stamina="10" staminaMax="10">
        <description>A Karossean soldier armed like yourself.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="352" escape="21" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="287" location="Unknown">
    <text>In the middle of your labour, you hear a grinding noise — and look up to see three huge tanks and a dozen grinning soldiers. Resistance would be useless. And, to add insult to injury, they do not treat you as a prisoner of war, but a common criminal. You are sent to a life of hard labour in the Karossean slave-pits. Your adventure is over— and it was not a heroic ending.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="288" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You are in the Arcade building. With your robot parked outside. It is a madhouse of sound and coloured lights. Each arcade game is wilder than the next. Which one will you play: Wasp Fighter? Dinosaur Hunt? Zap the Karossean? None Of these?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="221">
        <text>Wasp Fighter?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="393">
        <text>Dinosaur Hunt? Zap the Karossean?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="165">
        <text>Of these?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="289" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>As your robot falls, you pop out of the hatch and roll safely away. You crawl under a bush near the wall and wait. The great steel foot of the enemy robot lands close to your head as it charges in pursuit. But it merely puts a few more shots into your wrecked robot and continues past, without seeing you. As you lie in hiding, you hear other robots arrive, as well as troopers on foot. But they seem to be looking for an invading force, rather than a single fugitive. Eventually, most of them go inside the building — leaving one of their war robots standing empty, a stone's throw from your hiding-place!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="345">
        <text>If you make a dash for the robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="61">
        <text>If you stay in hiding.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="290" location="Capital City">
    <text>You clank through a small park and down a short street. In front of you, you see a crowd of Karossean soldiers, looting a shop.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="216">
        <text>If you turn and flee.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="343">
        <text>If you fight them.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="291" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You have defeated both the Triceratops. Lose STAMINA point due to the stress of the fight with the great horned dinosaurs. You realize that enter ing this area was a mistake; you will find nothing here but more danger! You quickly retrace your steps.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="189">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="292" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>As you examine the plant, you get the uneasy feeling that it is examining you too.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="248">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="293" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are shaken up; lose 1 STAMINA point. Because of the narrow jungle trails, your robot takes 3 points of damage as it escapes. Otherwise, you flee the jungle.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="294" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>The robot catches you. You must fight it as though it were a human opponent; this is a small robot, not a monster like the ones you have piloted, so your sharp sword may be enough to deal with its spindly arms! INFORMATION ROBOT SKILL 6 STAMINA 10</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Information Robot" skill="6" skillMax="6" stamina="10" staminaMax="10">
        <description>A small information robot with spindly metal arms.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="320" lose="344" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="295" location="City of Industry">
    <text>While you are arguing with the machine, it picks you up—none too gently— and tosses you back into the lift. Lose STAMINA point. If you leave the floor, and make a new selection.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>If you leave the floor.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="142">
        <text>and make a new selection. If you attack the robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="296" location="Capital City">
    <text>You escape easily. The guards have no idea what has happened. You have captured the Sword of State—a large, ornate blade. To your surprise, it is sharp and well balanced. When you use it to fight a foe, increase your SKILL by 1.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="358">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="297" location="Capital City">
    <text>The tyrant shakes his head. 'Just because you're a Thalian doesn't mean I have to duel you. Take him away!' You have done your best, but it wasn't enough. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="298" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You are leaving the City of the Jungle. Where will you go: The City of Industry? The City of Knowledge? The City of Pleasure? The Capital City? 30S</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>The City of Industry?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>The City of Knowledge?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="165">
        <text>The City of Pleasure?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="30">
        <text>The Capital City?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="299" location="City of Storms">
    <text>t You aim your weapons over their heads and fire a few times, hoping to herd them away from you. This is a mistake! They panic and run in all directions —and the narrow beach funnels many of them right at you. You are in the path of several hundred tonnes of frightened dinosaur! What will you do: Take off (if your robot can also fly)? Try to outrun them? Head for the water?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="371">
        <text>Take off (if your robot can also fly)? Try to outrun them?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="233">
        <text>Head for the water?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="300" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>It proves to be a useless volume of obscure military regulations. You cast it aside in irritation, but you have no time to examine another book.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="368">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="301" location="Capital City">
    <text>You quickly activate the Tangler Field. attacking flyers veer wildly. Two collide; several others crash into the ground. The survivors streak away in panic, and the sky is clear.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="156">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="302" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>As you leave the research labs, you hear once again the strange shuffling and squeaking. You step through a pair of double doors, into a room full of large wire cages. You see that some are opened. Then you realize what the sounds were. The hospi­tal's experimental animals have escaped... and they are hungry! You are facing a trio of red-eyed Giant Lizards.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="328">
        <text>Fight the creatures.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="350">
        <text>flee.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="303" location="Capital City">
    <text>You round a corner — and run right into three Karossean doctors! They look at you keenly. What will you do: Pretend to faint? Attack them? Apologize and go on your way?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="323">
        <text>Pretend to faint?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="353">
        <text>Attack them?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="375">
        <text>Apologize and go on your way?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="304" location="Capital City">
    <text>You are leaving the City of the Jungle. Where will you go?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="261">
        <text>If you stop to investigate it.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="57">
        <text>If you go straight to the temple.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="305" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Over the radio, the Karossean challenges you: T.ightyeight!' If you know the proper countersign for a response, that number. If not, you will have to fight.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="26">
        <text>If you do not know the countersign.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="306" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You bound out Of the wrecked robot and into the swamp, where the beast cannot follow.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="95">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="307" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The lift shoots quickly upward. The force of its acceleration almost knocks you down — and it continues for a long time! Suddenly the lift doors pop open. You are in the lobby Of the Robot Experimental Centre.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="206">
        <text>If you cross the square and re-enter your robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="25">
        <text>If you investigate the Robot Experimental Centre.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="308" location="Capital City">
    <text>You are in the Capital City - the seat of government of Thalos. It is a noble city, full of white marble buildings. It is also the main base of the invaders, and you know you must be very careful! Below, you have five options. Some of them will eventually return you to this paragraph. You may not make the same choice twice; each time you return here you must make a new selection. Where will you go:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="81">
        <text>The city hospital?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="10">
        <text>The Capitol Building?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="385">
        <text>The National Treasure House?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="4">
        <text>The enemy encampment?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="31">
        <text>Just explore?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="309" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You are leaving the City of Industry. Where will you go now?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>The City of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="165">
        <text>The City of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="38">
        <text>The City of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="122">
        <text>The City of Knowledge.</text>
        <condition>context.Inventory.Contains("City of Guardians Location")</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="310" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Trapped in the Dinosaur Preserve, without a robot to carry you, you have little hope. Test your Luck twice in succession.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="329">
        <text>If you are Lucky both times.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="348">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="311" location="Capital City">
    <text>Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="325">
        <text>If you are Lucky.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="108">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="312" location="Capital City">
    <text>You feel your robot tipping under you. A marshy spot! Instinctively, you put your machine in reverse. Tooslow... You sink slowly into the marsh. You try to fire your ejection seat, but it fails to function. You are doomed to a lingering death in the muck</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="313" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Roll one die.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>On a roll Of 1, 2 or 3.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="341">
        <text>On a roll of 4, 5 or 6.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="314" location="Capital City">
    <text>The tyrant shakes his head. 'Just because you're a Thalian doesn't mean I have to duel you.' But, hearing his men grumble, he adds: 'Until you prove yourself, that is. If you can defeat one of my officers, that will prove you are worthy to face me.' Instantly, one of his followers - a big, scarred brute - leaps out with drawn sword. Your sword is returned to you. You will have to fight the Karossean officer. OFFICER SKILL 11 STAMINA 11</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Officer" skill="11" skillMax="11" stamina="11" staminaMax="11">
        <description>A big, scarred Karossean officer.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="377" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="315" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You smash several pieces of furniture against the door, but to no avail. Your prison seems solid. Lose t STAMINA point.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="397">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="316" location="Unknown">
    <text>You regain control of your flyer, though the buffeting is terrible. Lose STAMINA point. If you have a flask of liquid in your possession, count the letters in both words of its name, multiply that number by 10, and that reference.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>If you have no flask.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="317" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You step cautiously inside, ready to fight if need be. But the sounds were being made by an automated repair facility, hard at work stamping out armourplate. There is no sign of anyone awake. You leave your robot and investigate the controls of the repair shop. They seem simple enough.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="59">
        <text>If you would like to attempt repairs on your robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="273">
        <text>If your robot needs no repairs, or if you do not choose to attempt repairs.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="318" location="City of Storms">
    <text>Unfortunately, your attempt fails. You are too slow to get out of the way. No matter how big your robot, the terrified beasts are bigger. Your adventure ends here, as you and your machine are both crushed into tin foil by a rampaging herd of dinosaurs.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="319" location="Unknown">
    <text>This is almost too easy! You proceed past the sentry as though everything were all right— then, at the last second, you change course. The last thing the sentry sees is the huge hulk of your machine looming over him.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="143">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="320" location="Unknown">
    <text>One by one, you chop off the robot's arms. At last it is helpless. You feel a bit sorry as you run out Of the door; the robot was only doing its duty. As you leave, it is still hooting mournfully, 'Return the museum's property, please!' You quickly climb into the control seat Of your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="396">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="321" location="Unknown">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="73">
        <text>If you explore the jungle on the Other path.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>If you want to go elsewhere.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="322" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You reach for the controls. The enemy pilots are still not in sight.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="381">
        <text>If you want to try to destroy the other robots.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="399">
        <text>If you just want to leave.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="323" location="Capital City">
    <text>The doctors pick you up and hoist you between them to a treatment room. Soon a robot surgeon is working on you. Restore your STAMINA to its Initial level. As soon as you are left alone in a recovery room, you take your leave. Unfortunately, your uniform is gone. You borrow suitable clothes from a sleeping man in the hallway and continue.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="395">
        <text>If you look for information on sleeping sickness.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>If you leave the hospital and return to your robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="324" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>Test your Luck.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="257">
        <text>If you are Unlucky.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="325" location="Capital City">
    <text>Ihe enemy robot's control bubble explodes in a cloud Of greasy black smoke. Small fragments clatter and ring off the pavement and your own armour. The headless body stands for a moment, then collapses in a pile of junk! One Karossean down, a thousand to go.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="290">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="326" location="Capital City">
    <text>There are far too many of them to fight. The area is littered with smoking wreckage before you are through. You have dealt a severe blow to the invaders, but you did not defeat them. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="327" location="Capital City">
    <text>You grit your teeth and summon up your courage — and go back inside. But it is worse than before. The Powers of Fear are all around you. Whatever help they may be able to give, you want none of it! Lose another SKI LL point and return.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Lose another SKI LL point and.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="328" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are facing three Giant Lizards! You back into the corner of the room, so that you may fight them one at a time. You cannot try to Escape until you have slain the first two.</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="First Giant Lizard" skill="7" skillMax="7" stamina="4" staminaMax="4">
        <description>A hungry escaped laboratory lizard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Second Giant Lizard" skill="6" skillMax="6" stamina="6" staminaMax="6">
        <description>A hungry escaped laboratory lizard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Third Giant Lizard" skill="7" skillMax="7" stamina="5" staminaMax="5">
        <description>A hungry escaped laboratory lizard.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="254" escape="254" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="329" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Torn and bleeding after several encounters with small dinosaurs, you stagger out of the Dinosaur Preserve. Lose 3 STAMINA points, one at a time (so, if you have medikits, you can cure each one as it is lost).</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="364">
        <text>If you have already investigated the unmarked building.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="383">
        <text>If you have not investigated that building.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="330" location="Capital City">
    <text>Minos draws a huge, jewelled sword. You know he did not become Tyrant of Karossea by being soft or weak. But you didn't get this far by being weak, either. 'Defend yourself, Karossean!' you shout. A murmur - could it be approval? - rises from the watching officers. You battle Minos - to the death! MINOS SKILL 12 STAMINA 12</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Minos" skill="12" skillMax="12" stamina="12" staminaMax="12">
        <description>The Tyrant of Karossea, armed with a huge jewelled sword.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="355" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="331" location="Unknown">
    <text>You nee from the Nothosaurus.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="382">
        <text>If you are in a robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="279">
        <text>If you are on foot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="332" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>As you approach the War College, you see two Karossean robots guarding it, and black-clad foot soldiers milling about. Fortunately, you were cautious in your approach, and they have not seen you, There can be nothing here worth entering that hornets' nest for! You quickly change course.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="147">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="333" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You are in the lobby of the Robot Experimental Centre. You read the directory, and see that different sorts of work are being done on different floors of the building. Severall seem interesting. Where will you go:</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="392">
        <text>Second floor: Interface Mechanisms.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="182">
        <text>Third floor: Weapons Development.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="20">
        <text>Sixth floor: Amplifier Project.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="229">
        <text>Tenth floor: Deteronics.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="206">
        <text>Leave the building.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="334" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have defeated the guards. Other soldiers are running from all directions, but they cannot see you. You have captured the Sword of State, a large, ornate blade. TO your surprise, it is sharp and well balanced. When you use it to fight a foe, increase your SKILL by 1.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="358">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="335" location="City of Storms">
    <text>You pilot your robot along the sea-coast.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="284">
        <text>If you are flying.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="8">
        <text>If you are not flying.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="336" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Your robot falls and you lie stunned in the wreckage. The tentacles of a Tripod pull you out. You are a prisoner of the Karosseans! You have failed in your mission. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="337" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>'Correct,' replies the computer. 'All Thalian personnel have been disabled by Karossean attack using Sudden Sleeping Sickness. My sensors show no other citizen of Thalos still awake. You are granted base entry at Level Zero.'</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="175">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="338" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>You have no control over the Borer Robot's path. For hours it tunnels underground; then it turns upward again. Eventually it reaches the surface, and you open the hatch into daylight. You seem to be in a small town. You will need to find new transportation; the Borer Robot will not stir from its new site. The only robot you can find to take you there, unfortunately, is an ancient, rattling Stilter. Thisisa very tall, thin robot, apparently designed for painting the upper storeys of buildings or something of the sort. Its arms and legs are very long. You hope this tired, creaky machine will make the trip safely. STILTER ARMOUR 4 srEED Medium COMBAT BONUS —t SPECIAL A BILITIES: None You are midway between two cities.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="361">
        <text>If you will go to the City Of Knowledge.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>If you will go to the City of Worship.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="339" location="Capital City">
    <text>You decide to visit the Temple of Glory. After all, glory is what you will earn if you can drive off the Karosseans! The temple is large and stately, with multicoloured mosaics of battle scenes on the outer walls. You enter and approach the altar. You feel the presence Of the Powers Of Glory very strongly. A voice seems to ring in your head: 'Are you willing to risk all for glory?'</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="286">
        <text>'Are you willing to risk all for glory?' If your reply is 'Yes'.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="149">
        <text>If it is 'No'.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="340" location="City of Industry">
    <text>This area proves to be full of rusting, abandoned robots. At the other side of the vault is a huge lift. The control panel has three coloured buttons, but none is marked. The lift containsa huge robot; in the dimness, you cannot make out what type it is, but it has treads and claws.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="269">
        <text>If you enter the lift and push a button at random.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="398">
        <text>If you take the small corridor beside the lift.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="341" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>As you speed over the jungle, your instruments warn of an enemy approaching. It is a single Karossean in a captured fighter-craft. He has somehow identified you as a foe; he is already attacking. His robot is a Wasp Fighter, a sleek experimental machine. Only a few exist. It has very little armour, but it has good weapons and handles well. WASP FIGHTER ARMOUR 6 SPEED Very Fast SKILL 11 SPECIAL ABILITIES: Whenever the Wasp's Attack Roll exceeds its foe's roll by 4 or more, it has literally flown circles around its foe! It automatically wins the next combat round - no rolls are necessary. You cannot Escape.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Wasp Fighter" frame="Unspecified" armor="6" armorMax="6" skill="11" skillMax="11" speed="Very Fast" speedMax="Very Fast">
        <description>A sleek experimental Karossean fighter-craft.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="137" lose="60" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="342" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Down a side-street you hear the sounds Of purpose ful action. Peering cautiously around the comer, you see that the sounds—banging, clanging noises— are coming from a shop marked 'Robot Repair'. The shop door, naturally, is big enougl. for a robot to enter, and is invitingly open. If you go on your way, to.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="317">
        <text>If you enter and investigate.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="343" location="Capital City">
    <text>They scatter in fear — all but one. He climbs into a large Construction Robot near by and pilots it towards you. If your own robot is faster than Slow, you can Escape.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="216">
        <text>If your own robot is faster than Slow, you can Escape (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="386">
        <text>). If you would rather fight.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="344" location="Unknown">
    <text>The robot overcomes you and takes the Amulet of Luck away from you. Muttering to itself, it rolls Off to be repaired. You lie on the floor, unable to fight further. Lose 2 L VCK points, and reduce your Initial LUCK back to its starting score. You struggle back outside to your own robot and climb in.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="396">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="345" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Laughing, you scramble into an enemy combat robot! The Myrmidon is the standard Karossean combat robot. It has two forms - humanoid and fighter-plane. MYRMIDON Human Form ARMOUR 12 SPEED Medium COMBAT BONUS +1 Plane Form ARMOUR 10 SPEED Very Fast COMBAT BONUS +1 SPECIAL ABILITIES: The Myrmidon can change shape - from humanoid to aircraft, and back. The Myrmidon takes one combat change forms. During that turn, the robot makes its normal combat roll, but if it wins, it does no damage to the foe - it just defends itself. If you are not in combat, the robot can change shapes freely, with no penalty of any kind - except that if the robot is in humanoid shape and has 2 or less ARMOUR points, it will fall apart if it changes to a plane! The controls are unfamiliar. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="322">
        <text>If you have read the manual on Karossean robots.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="3">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <robots>
      <robot tag="Robot" name="Myrmidon" frame="Humanoid" armor="12" armorMax="12" speed="Average" speedMax="Average" combatBonus="1" combatBonusMax="1">
        <description>A Karossean combat robot that can change between humanoid and fighter-plane forms.</description>
      </robot>
    </robots>
  </block>
  <block id="346" location="Capital City">
    <text>With the Cargo Crab, you can carry hundreds of pounds of gold.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="287">
        <text>Load up the Cargo Crab.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Leave the Treasure House empty-handed.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="347" location="Unknown">
    <text>Seconds after you climb back into the robot, ittoo explodes. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="348" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Your adventure ends here, in the stomach of a dinosaur..</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="349" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have run into a group of Karosseans patrolling the city! They do not have war machines, but have taken over several of the city's own robots. If your own speed is Very Fast, you may escape them before the battle starts by leaving the city. Otherwise, you must fight them one at a time, in order. None of these robots has any special abilities. Once the battle starts, you may not Escape.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="298">
        <text>If your own speed is Very Fast, escape before the battle starts.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Street Cleaner" frame="Unspecified" armor="4" armorMax="4" skill="7" skillMax="7" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow">
        <description>A city robot taken over by Karossean patrols.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" lose="154" />
      </monster>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Towing Robot" frame="Unspecified" armor="6" armorMax="6" skill="7" skillMax="7" speed="Average" speedMax="Average">
        <description>A city robot taken over by Karossean patrols.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" lose="154" />
      </monster>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Traffic Copter" frame="Unspecified" armor="3" armorMax="3" skill="8" skillMax="8" speed="Fast" speedMax="Fast">
        <description>A city robot taken over by Karossean patrols.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="35" lose="154" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="350" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>Test your Luck. If you are Lucky, you make it back to your robot without incident. If you are Unlucky, you trip and fall on the precious flask of Blue Potion. It is broken and lost. You arrive back at your robot just ahead of the pursuing beasts.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="210">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="351" location="Unknown">
    <text>You dive into the water, activating the 'jets' that let your machine swim. You are still in danger — the herd is not just on the land, but thundering through the shallow water as well. But, in the nick of time, you escape them.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>If you Return to the city.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="246">
        <text>If you try to swim around the herd and investigate the spot where they were originally clustered.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="352" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have defeated your foe. His body vanishes as though it had never existed. Though the temple is silent, you seem to hear victory trumpets. Restore your STA MINA to its Initial score, and increase your SKILL and your Initial SKILL by (for personal combat only). you may not visit this temple again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="353" location="Capital City">
    <text>You may fight them one at a time: First DOCTOR SKILL 7 STAMINA 5 Second DOCTOR SKILL 6 STAMINA 7 Third DOCTOR SKILL 6 STAMINA 5 You cannot Escape; you must silence them quickly.</text>
    <enemies>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="First Doctor" stamina="5" staminaMax="5" skill="7" skillMax="7">
        <description>A Karossean doctor trying to raise the alarm.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Second Doctor" stamina="7" staminaMax="7" skill="6" skillMax="6">
        <description>A Karossean doctor trying to raise the alarm.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="-1" />
      </enemy>
      <enemy tag="Enemy" name="Third Doctor" stamina="5" staminaMax="5" skill="6" skillMax="6">
        <description>A Karossean doctor trying to raise the alarm.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="308" />
      </enemy>
    </enemies>
  </block>
  <block id="354" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have defeated Minos and his Supertank. Around you is devastation; the few smaller robots you can see are fleeing in panic. The invasion force is routed and broken. You know that in a week or so, your people will recover on their own, and you will be a hero. But right now, all you want is some rest. With none to oppose you, you turn your robot homeward. Your adventure is over... and you are victorious!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="355" location="Capital City">
    <text>You have slain Minos in fair combat! By ancient custom Of the Karosseans, his tribe — the whole Karossean nation — must now submit to your judgement. Needless to say, you order that they awaken your people, and leave your country with all their men and machines. And they do! Before you know it, things are back to normal. Almost One little thing is different. The day on which you defeated Minos is now a national holiday — named after you. You are, truly and for ever, a hero.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="356" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You set off into the jungle, along a path wide enough for a robot - or a dinosaur. Soon the path forks.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="19">
        <text>If you go right.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="357" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>In the middle of a sentence, your explanations are stilled for ever by the fire from hidden guns. The computer has made a fatal mistake... fatal for you as well. Your adventure is over.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="358" location="Capital City">
    <text>The Cloak of Invisibility is beginning to flicker. You Will not be able to use it again. Before it expires, you make your way out of the Capitol Building and back to your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="359" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>If you know the Wasp Fighter's model number, use that reference number. If not, continue.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="23">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="360" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You poke around, looking for something useful. You find nothing. but a huge book falls from a high shelf and hits you on the head. Lose STAMINA point. The other bookshelves are teetering ominously. You leave in disgust and return to the lobby.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="361" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are in the City of Knowledge. Here are all of Thalos's greatest universities and museums. This is the home of those who most value learning. Here, you hope, you will find something to help you in your lone struggle. You have a wide choice of possible destinations within the City of Knowledge.</text>
    <revisitText>You are back in the City of Knowledge.</revisitText>
    <choices>
      <choice to="40">
        <text>Keep going to the city.</text>
        <condition>context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="54">
        <text>The College of Medicine.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="14">
        <text>The Thalian Museum.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="66">
        <text>Dinosaur Preserve.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="277">
        <text>The War College.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
      <choice to="380">
        <text>Out of the city.</text>
        <condition>!context.City.IsVisited</condition>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="362" location="Unknown">
    <text>You cannot escape in time. A blast nicl$ your robds armour. Lose ARMOUR point and wheel to fight your foes.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="169">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="363" location="Unknown">
    <text>As you prepare to leave, it occurs to you that a few bars of this treasure— or, perhaps, more than a few— would be a fair compensation for your troubles so far. If not.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="346">
        <text>If you have taken the Cargo Crab.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="220">
        <text>If not.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="364" location="Unknown">
    <text>Fortunately, you left the robot building open. You may now return there and get a robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="9">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="365" location="Capital City">
    <text>You decide to visit the Temple of Peace. It is a relatively small building in this city of great temples, but easy to find; it is surrounded on all sides by a cool green park. You leave your robot at the edge of the park and walk towards the temple, rather than take a war machine to the Temple of Peace. Somehow, you feel certain that nothing will harm you. The temple is full of sleeping worshippers— but they all wear gentle smiles, and you are sure their dreams are untroubled. You feel moved to pray. What will you pray for: Complete peace? Strength in battle? Freedom?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="37">
        <text>Complete peace?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="390">
        <text>Strength in battle?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="107">
        <text>Freedom?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="366" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>You decide to explore the city.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="16">
        <text>If you explore the northern portion.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="225">
        <text>If you explore to the south.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="367" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Undaunted, you continue towards the City of Industry on foot. Test your Luck again. If you are Unlucky, you lose another 3 STAMINA points to exposure. If you are Lucky, you find shelter and water in the wasteland. Eventually, you find a little robot car and finish the trip to the City of Industry. The robot car is a small four-wheeled vehicle, designed for pleasure, but definitely not for combat! ROBOT CAR ARMOURO SPEED Fast COMBAT BONUS O SPECIAL ABILITIES: This little machine is totally unsuited for fighting! If it is attacked by anything faster, it automatically loses. If attacked by something slower, it can Escape if given the chance. Your car passes through the gates of the City of Industry.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="368" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You realize that you must leave quickly. Looking outside, you see that the Karosseans have entered the building. The fools have left their robots outside and unguarded, parked near yours. You spring out of the window and run for them.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="322">
        <text>If you get back into your own robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="345">
        <text>If you get into a Karossean robot instead.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="369" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The lift doors shudder, and the lift drops half a metre and stops. The lights flicker on, and then off. If you push another button, return and choose again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="269">
        <text>If you push another button.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="398">
        <text>and choose again. If you leave the lift and enter the corridor beside it.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="370" location="City of Industry">
    <text>You look around the junkyard, and see several things that might be of use. But then you are confronted by a huge creature with the remains of a collar around its neck. It is a Giant Ape, carrying the leg of a robot as though it were a club! At the moment, it seems curious rather than angry. What will you do: Flee? Speak to the Ape? Attack the Ape?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="110">
        <text>Flee?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="234">
        <text>Speak to the Ape?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="138">
        <text>Attack the Ape?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="371" location="City of Storms">
    <text></text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="196">
        <text>If your robot is Very Fast or Fast (ground speed only).</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="318">
        <text>If it is Medium or Slow.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="372" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You read through the book one last time... and discover an alarming footnote. One of the ingre dients you used was Essence of Man-trap Flower. But, according to the footnote, this essence loses its power over time. It may be that the material you used was weak or even totally worthless! The only way to be absolutely certain of success would be either to find some brartd-new essence, or to acquire a fresh Man-trap Flower and add it to your flask of Potion. But you have no idea where to look for fresh essence, and the flower itself grows only in the deepest jungle.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="302">
        <text>Pack the fragile bottle of Blue Potion carefully and set out for your robot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="373" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You stretch a robot arm to its fullest extension and pluck one of the flowers. The plant shudders.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="211">
        <text>If you possess a Blue Potion.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="248">
        <text></text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="374" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You find a stairway and head down. You find that both the Karosseans are dead. One was about your size; you quickly strip off his unifonn and put it on yourself. It may come in handy later! You check the signs. The demolished exhibit was labelled 'Tyrannosaurus'. The shouts from outside are coming closer, so you duck out of a convenient door.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="1014">
        <text>Return to the front desk.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="375" location="Capital City">
    <text>As you walk down the hallway, you sense eyes boring into your back. Then the doctors run down the hall away from you, shouting! Evidently your accent gave you away. You cannot catch them; you hurriedly flee from the hospital and back to the place where you left your robot (if you havea robot). Lose STAMINA point.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="376" location="City of the Guardians">
    <text>You are leaving the City of the Guardians.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="144">
        <text>If you decide to go to the City of Storms.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>If you decide to go to the City of Industry.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="377" location="Capital City">
    <text>Your opponent falls, mortally wounded. A gasp goes up from the circle of officers watching the battle. As you reel back, one of them catches you. You see Minos dusting off his hands and drawing his sword. 'Here! Drink this!' says the Karossean officer who kept you from falling.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="388">
        <text>If you drink the flask he offers.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="330">
        <text>If you decline.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="378" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You are leaving the City of Pleasure.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>If you would like to go to the City of Industry.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="274">
        <text>If you would like to go to the City of the Jungle.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="379" location="Unknown">
    <text>To your horror, you are caught in a downdraught! Your robot falls, spinning. You are thrown against the side Of the cockpit. Around you, metal shrieks. Lose 2 STAMINA points; your robot loses 2 ARMOUR points. If either STAMINA or ARMOUR is reduced too, you aredead. If not, you have a chance to regain control.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="12">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="380" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are leaving the City of Knowledge... hopefulIy, wiser than when you came. Where will you travel now: The City of Industry? The City Of the Jungle? The City of Storms?... The City of Worship?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="265">
        <text>The City of Industry?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>The City Of the Jungle?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="179">
        <text>The City of Storms?...</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>The City of Worship?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="381" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>Without their pilots, the other robots are defenceless. Your own machine quickly hammers them into junk. But as you attack the last one, it fights back! Evidently it was left on autopilot. Your own robot loses 3 ARMOUR points before you can destroy that last foe. You leave the War College at top speed, with the Karossean pilots shouting angrily behind you from the windows. But you have lost part of the advantage of surprise; the Karosseans now know that at least one person remains awake to oppose their scheme!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="147">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="382" location="Unknown">
    <text>3S2 Lose 2 LUCK points for abandoning the sleepers to the tender mercies Of the hungry dinosaur. If you have not already explored the south of the city, you may do so. Otherwise,</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="225">
        <text>If you have not already explored the south of the city, you may do so (.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="137">
        <text>).</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="383" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You wander around for hours, but the Administra tion Building is useless, and the other building is tightly locked and you cannot enter it. You must leave the Dinosaur Preserve and see what you can find. Unfortunately, the Dinosaur Preserve is far away from the rest of the City of Knowledge. After an hour of walking, the best you have been able to find is a battered old Farm Robot. FARM ROBOT ARMOUR 7 spEEDMedium COMBAT BONVSO SPECIAL ABILITIES: None But it is better than nothing, so you take it.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="150">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="384" location="Capital City">
    <text>You are caught in the remains of your robot as the Crusher's enormous foot comes down one last time. Your end is mercifully quick.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="385" location="Unknown">
    <text>You have arrived at the National Treasure House. A great, grey building, it is the repository of all IhaIOS's gold. To your surprise, it is guarded only by a single Karossean sentry, standing in front of the building.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="319">
        <text>If you have a robot.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="271">
        <text>If you are on foot.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="386" location="Capital City">
    <text>The enemy Construction Robot raises huge claws and moves towards you. It rolls on eight vast wheels. It has only a few guns, to protect against attacking dinosaurs, but it has four huge arms mounted all around. CONSTRUCTION ROBOT ARMOUR 9 SPEED Slow SKILL 6 SPECIAL ABILITIES: None. Fortunately for you, the Karossean soldier inside does not really know how to use this robot. If the enemy mishandles the controls, use the special option.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="194">
        <text>If the enemy mishandles the controls.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Construction Robot" frame="Unspecified" armor="9" armorMax="9" skill="6" skillMax="6" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow">
        <description>A huge eight-wheeled construction machine with four claws.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="92" lose="61" escape="216" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
  <block id="387" location="City of Storms">
    <text>The placid beasts are quite familiar with robots; they honk and hiss, but move over to let you through.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="62">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="388" location="Capital City">
    <text>You drink. A tingling goes through your body. 'You put up a good show!' says the officer in a whisper. 'By law, you shouldn't have to duel Minos until you can rest, but he's coming for you right now. This will even the odds.' You thank him for his sportsmanship. Obviously not all Karosseans are totally bad! The officer's healing drink gives you 4 STAMINA points, or restores you to your Initial STAMINA, whichever is less.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="330">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="389" location="Unknown">
    <text>3S9 The Karosseans fire on you. Lose ARMOUR point and fight.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="169">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="390" location="Unknown">
    <text>The room somehow seems colder. The feeling of peace evaporates (lose LUCK point). Quickly you rise and walk back to your robot. You realize that your request was inappropriate. you may not visit this temple again.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="166">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="391" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Your luck has run out! The Tyrannosaurus spots you and gobbles you up in a second. Your adven-, ture is over — and a short one it was, too.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="-1">
        <text>Return to ending screen.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="392" location="City of Industry">
    <text>Exp1oring the second floor, you find several proto typemodels of an odd-looking helmet. According to the files you read there, it is an Interface Transponder. While you wear one of these helmets, increase your skill by1 when using a robot. It does not affect other combats.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="333">
        <text>Explore the Centre further.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="206">
        <text>Leave the Centre and return to your robot outside.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <items>
      <item tag="Interface Transponder" name="Interface Transponder" icon="interface_transponder.png">
        <description>+1 skill with robots.</description>
        <onAcquire>
          <effect>context.Player.RobotSkill++</effect>
        </onAcquire>
        <onDiscard>
          <effect>context.Player.RobotSkill--</effect>
        </onDiscard>
      </item>
    </items>
  </block>
  <block id="393" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You step into the game and pick up the toy ray-gun that comes With it. A light comes on and you see yourself in a mirror — but a holographic trick has clothed your reflection in a beard and a Karossean uniform. You laugh and fire at it. Unfortunately, with all the repairmen sleeping, this machine is out of order. When you fire, you receive a severe electrical shock. Roll one die. On 1, 2 or 3, you lose point of SKILL On 4, 5 or 6, you lose point of STAM r NÅ.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="288">
        <text>If you want to play another game.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="165">
        <text>If you want to leave the Arcade.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="394" location="City of Pleasure">
    <text>You pack the fragile bottle of Blue Potion carefully, and set out for your robot.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="302">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="395" location="Capital City">
    <text>You dash down the hallway, following the signs marked 'Library'. You turn a corner and run headlong into a Karossean guard! You finish him off before he can summon aid, but he wounds you slightly: lose STAMINA point. Once at the library, you ransack it for information on sleeping sickness. But you find nothing; the relevant volumes are all missing. You realize this has been a wild-goose chase. Carefully, you Slip out Of the hospital and away.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="308">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="396" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You are leaving the Thalian Museum. Where would you like to go now: The College of War? The Dinosaur Preserve? The College of Medicine? Out of the city?</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="277">
        <text>The College of War?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="66">
        <text>The Dinosaur Preserve?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="54">
        <text>The College of Medicine?</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="380">
        <text>Out of the city?</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="397" location="City of the Jungle">
    <text>After a few hours, the door opens and a soldier tosses in a package of rations. Desperately, you grab his arm before the door closes! The Karossean turn. bles to the floor. He has no chance against your berserk rage. You leave him unconscious, at a cost of 2 STAMINA points to yourself. In an adjoining room, you find your sword lying underneath a table, but there is no sign of your other Possessions.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="174">
        <text>If you search for them.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="69">
        <text>If you leave immediately.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="398" location="City of Industry">
    <text>The corridor levels off and passes a small alcove. Within the alcove is a small lift, just big enough for one person.</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="307">
        <text>If you want to get in the lift and press the button.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice to="178">
        <text>If you continue along the corridor.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="399" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You speed away. Behind you, the Karossean pilots come charging out of the building, heading for their robots. But you know the city better than they do; though they hunt for you, your head start is enough to see you safely away. But you have lost part of the advantage of surprise; the Karosseans now know that at least one person remains awake to oppose their scheme!</text>
    <choices>
      <choice to="147">
        <text>Continue.</text>
      </choice>
    </choices>
  </block>
  <block id="400" location="City of Knowledge">
    <text>You fight the Ankylosaurus. This small but powerful dinosaur is studded with armour-plate. Its tail is tipped with a huge ball of bone which it swings like a mace.</text>
    <monsters>
      <monster tag="Monster" name="Ankylosaurus" frame="Dinosaur" armor="12" armorMax="12" skill="9" skillMax="9" speed="Slow" speedMax="Slow">
        <description>A small but powerful dinosaur with armoured-plate.</description>
        <battleOutcome win="56" escape="115" />
      </monster>
    </monsters>
  </block>
</book>